<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" 
  xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>matrix on Mr. Blogger</title>
    <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/tags/matrix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in matrix on Mr. Blogger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><hosted>Netlify -- netlify.com</hosted>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 11:38:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    
        <atom:link href="https://mistrysiddh.tk/tags/matrix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    

      
      <item>
        <title>Are We Living in Simulation Part 6</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-6/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 11:38:49 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 17:30:55 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-6/</guid>
        <description>Recap As in part 1, we have talked about Quantum Computers, Facebook AI Chat, and Predictions of AI Robots wherein part 2 we had a recap of part 1 and also The Matrix movie, Roswell UFO Incident, wherein part 3 we discussed on MKUltra performed by US Central Intelligence Agency, Black Mirror: Bandersnatch movie where you can control Stefan Butler by given two choices which leads to a different path in the movies.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&#34;recap&#34;&gt;Recap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation/&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;, we have talked about &lt;strong&gt;Quantum Computers&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Facebook AI Chat&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Predictions of AI Robots&lt;/strong&gt; wherein &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-2/&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt; we had a recap of &lt;strong&gt;part 1&lt;/strong&gt; and also &lt;strong&gt;The Matrix&lt;/strong&gt; movie, &lt;strong&gt;Roswell UFO Incident&lt;/strong&gt;, wherein &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/&#34;&gt;part 3&lt;/a&gt; we discussed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/#what-is-mkultra&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MKUltra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; performed by &lt;code&gt;US Central Intelligence Agency&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/#black-mirror-bandersnatch&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Black Mirror: Bandersnatch&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; movie where you can control &lt;strong&gt;Stefan Butler&lt;/strong&gt; by given two choices which leads to a different path in the movies. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-4/&#34;&gt;part 4&lt;/a&gt; we talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-4/#ufo&#34;&gt;UFO&lt;/a&gt; also we seen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-4/#space-mysteries&#34;&gt;Space Mysteries&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;code&gt;Restored Apollo 11&lt;/code&gt; and also we saw the video a mysterious video where an unidentified spacecraft refuelling itself from the sun. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/&#34;&gt;part 5&lt;/a&gt; we talked about time travel where we seen some of the most known time travel and reference in the article about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/#who-was-sid-hurwich&#34;&gt;Sid Hurwich&lt;/a&gt; which was about time machine which can &lt;code&gt;Freeze Time&lt;/code&gt;, also we saw many mysteries of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/#mike-tyson-match&#34;&gt;Mike Tyson Match&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/#charlie-chaplin-moive&#34;&gt;Charlie Chaplin Moive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/#london-bridge-opening&#34;&gt;London Bridge Opening&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/#a-man-from-2256&#34;&gt;A man from 2256&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/#swiss-ring-watch&#34;&gt;Swiss ring watch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/#1500-years-old-mummy-wearing-adidas-sneaker-shoe&#34;&gt;1500 years old mummy wearing Adidas sneaker shoe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/#17th-century-astronaut&#34;&gt;17th century astronaut&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/#the-man-from-taured&#34;&gt;The man from Taured&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/#john-titor&#34;&gt;John Titor&lt;/a&gt; well if the time travel is possible then it would be much more terrifying then we thought because they can go back to time and change the future or can destroy the future but there are many rules of travelling back or forward in time.&lt;/p&gt;




  



  &lt;div class=&#34;featured-image__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/cicada-3301.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Featured Image&#34; class=&#34;featured-image&#34; style=&#34;width: ;height: ;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cicada-3301&#34;&gt;Cicada 3301&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;everything-you-need-to-know-about-cicada-3301-an-internet-mystery&#34;&gt;Everything you need to know about Cicada 3301 (An internet Mystery)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of late, you can find several puzzle games online available in the market for users all around the world. These puzzle games are easy to play and you are not going to face any issues or confusion for sure. But Cicada 3301 is something different from those types of puzzle games which you might have played in the past with your family members and relatives in your free time. On the year 4th January 2012, the mysterious and hardest puzzle on the internet was launched named “Cicada 3301”. It is one of the most mysterious and elaborate puzzles available today for people across the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of the puzzles each year has been to carefully recruit the best and talented individuals. But the ultimate purpose is still not known to the people. As per some reviews, it has been stated that Cicada 3301 is mainly a secret society to improve privacy, cryptography, and anonymity. It would be better for you to understand that the name Cicada 3301 is given to a mysterious internet organization which has published sets of puzzle several times to recruit the most intelligent and fastest code breakers from all around the world. This puzzle was first published on sites like 4chan and Reddit and remains active for nearly a month. Do you want to know more about the Cicada 3301 and how it works? If yes is your answer, then here you would get all the information you are looking for right now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-the-points-of-cicada-3301&#34;&gt;What are the Points of Cicada 3301?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main point of Cicada 3301 is to recruit highly intelligent and educated fast code breakers from all over the world through the sets of puzzles. They are looking for highly experienced and talented individuals. To search them, they have devised a test. Also, there is a message hidden in the image and you need to find them to reach them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-did-cicada-3301-start&#34;&gt;When did Cicada 3301 start?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/cicada-3301.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cicada 3301&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the year 4th of January 2012, the mysterious and hardest puzzle on the internet was launched named “Cicada 3301”. It is one of the most mysterious and elaborate puzzles available today for people worldwide. It is a puzzle where you need to have a good deal of technical knowledge, an understanding of number theory, including philosophy, classical music, knowledge of artist references, technological references, Mayan numerology, mathematics, cyberpunk literature, and the life cycles of cicadas. As per some speculations, Cicada 3301 is well-funded and large, considering that it has the deep knowledge to create such complex puzzles and at the same time, capable of supporting the existence of clues in a large number of locations, all far from one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the year 2012, it was started, and then soon after one year, it again started for the people to solve the puzzles. There are thousands of people who have tried to solve the puzzle from their side but not able to do it due to a lack of intelligent and education skills. The puzzle looks similar to other online puzzles but very difficult to solve it. You should be well educated and highly intelligent for solving it easily without any problem. The mysterious organization Cicada 3301 has been releasing online encryptions since 2012, drawing top code-breakers to accept the challenges and nobody knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-is-cicada-3301&#34;&gt;Who is Cicada 3301?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cicada 3301 is a nickname given to an organization and it is not related to a particular person. All the set of puzzles to hire code breakers mainly focused on steganography, data security, cryptography, and even internet anonymity. Most people have claimed recently that Cicada 3301 is a secret society to improve anonymity, privacy, and cryptography. Some others have claimed that Cicada 3301 is a cult or religion. By considering the official statement of people who won the 2012 puzzle, 3301 uses non-puzzle based recruiting methods but created the puzzles because they were only looking for educated members with computer security and cryptography skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-the-mission-of-cicada-3301&#34;&gt;What is the mission of Cicada 3301?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/mission-cicada-3301.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Mission&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main mission of Cicada 3301 is still not known to the people due to its mysterious nature of work. As per some people reviews, it has been cleared that it is mainly for hiring intelligent and educated people in the organization. But the type of organization is still not known to the people and expected to be revealed very soon in the future for sure. This mysterious organization is trying to recruit the fastest and intelligent code breakers from all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-happens-to-those-who-solve-cicada-3301&#34;&gt;What happens to those who solve cicada 3301?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those people who solve cicada 3301 still in a dilemma and they are not able to understand what is the main reason behind creating those puzzles. In a recent interview, Puzzle solvers have also mentioned the puzzles they have solved from their end and how it is not so easy for them in the beginning. It is an internet mystery and people are getting aware of it. Many folks have tried from their end but some of them become successful and some of them did not get much success in solving those highly complex problems. It is expected that soon a new puzzle set will be published on the site and people are waiting to try their luck. In the future, it has been cleared that people will show more excitement and eagerness to solve these puzzles, and soon we will come to know about some more people who are giving it a try for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_sepWhNGopg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-was-the-purpose-of-cicasa-3301&#34;&gt;What was the purpose of Cicasa 3301?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is normally believed that the results of solving the puzzle would lead the individuals to better know who these people are. As a participant, you are going to solve one puzzle and then another puzzle will be given to you with much-increasing difficulty level for sure. All the participants need to have high and strong knowledge regarding “Cryptography, coding, Steganography, Encryption, and many more. It is a famous mystery as people want to know who these people who have started this puzzle. Also, want to know the main reason behind hiring such intelligent individuals in a team. As per certain claims, it is believed it to be a secret society while others normally believed that Cicada 3301 is a religion or cult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a9z7LPBMHTg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2013, it was the time of round 3 puzzles. Once again the image includes the message and the message led to the book and also book led to the link. The procedure was the same as before but this time message led to the book named “ Liber Primus” ( First book). The book was written in Latin and originated from Russia. The book was a mystery for most people and many still not able to know the exact reason behind it. However, a significant portion of the book has yet to be translated. Out of 74 pages, only 19 pages have been successfully translated. From the year 2015 to now, no puzzles have been found but still internet users all around the world waiting for this mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you are aware of the Cicada 3301 and how it was solved by Joel and Marcus. All the above-mentioned points will help you in knowing what is Cicada 3301 and how it becomes an internet mystery for the users worldwide. You should note that the Cicada puzzle is not simple as most of the other puzzles available online and you need to be very educated and highly intelligent for solving the complex puzzles for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the full solution of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL2nkG_LEeBQFu0m2bS5E1-EN3JgzpUe7g&#34;&gt;Cicada 3301&lt;/a&gt; puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ra858de45f56d9bc9&#34;&gt;r/A858DE45F56D9BC9&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/r-A858DE45F56D9BC9.png&#34; alt=&#34;r/A858DE45F56D9BC9&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started back in 2011 when a Reddit account began posting an indecipherable sequence of numbers and letters to a new subreddit, r/A858DE45F56D9BC9, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/A858DE45F56D9BC9&#34;&gt;r/A858&lt;/a&gt; for short. After languishing in Internet obscurity for nearly a year, another Reddit user requested more information, asking: &amp;ldquo;Do these seemingly random strings of numbers &amp;hellip; correlate to something; is there some big joke I’m missing out on?&amp;rdquo; There was no reply, but enough people began to wonder the same thing themselves, and soon a sister subreddit, r/Solving_A858, was born. It consisted of &amp;ldquo;a dedicated group of computer science students, amateur cryptographers, and motivated enthusiasts&amp;rdquo; working together to crack the code, if indeed that&amp;rsquo;s what it was, reports the Daily Dot. At first, the creator kept the subreddit private, with only those proving themselves worthy allowed in, but it eventually opened to the public. It all started back in 2011 when a Reddit account began posting an indecipherable sequence of numbers and letters to a new subreddit, r/A858DE45F56D9BC9, or r/A858 for short. After languishing in Internet obscurity for nearly a year, another Reddit user requested more information, asking: &amp;ldquo;Do these seemingly random strings of numbers &amp;hellip; correlate to something; is there some big joke I’m missing out on?&amp;rdquo; There was no reply, but enough people began to wonder the same thing themselves, and soon a sister subreddit, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Solving_A858/&#34;&gt;r/Solving_A858&lt;/a&gt;, was born. It consisted of &amp;ldquo;a dedicated group of computer science students, amateur cryptographers, and motivated enthusiasts&amp;rdquo; working together to crack the code, if indeed that&amp;rsquo;s what it was, reports the Daily Dot. At first, the creator kept the subreddit private, with only those proving themselves worthy allowed in, but it eventually opened to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today only a few of the thousands of r/A858 posts have been decoded, but they tend to be cryptic—such as an excerpt from the book Actions and Passions by Max Lerner and the ASCII image of Stonehenge, reported Bustle last year. The subreddit creator was pretty much silent until August 2015 when an account appeared in the sister &amp;ldquo;solving&amp;rdquo; subreddit that (after appropriate code-breaking, of course) allowed users to ask questions. Still, any answers were themselves cryptic, such as: &amp;ldquo;We cannot disclose the purpose. A858 will end when the purpose is disclosed or discovered.&amp;rdquo; Then on March 29, after having been private for some time (it switches between private and public regularly), r/A858 suddenly read: &amp;ldquo;The A858 Project Has Concluded. You may unsubscribe.&amp;rdquo; Many still think the project isn&amp;rsquo;t over. &amp;ldquo;I only hope A858 has a purpose,&amp;rdquo; one user writes. &amp;ldquo;I don’t particularly care if it is a good one.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;india&#34;&gt;India&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://alochonaa.files.wordpress.com/2014/02/india.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;India&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India has been called the land of mysteries since time immemorial, whether for its various enigmatic natural phenomena or eccentricities associated with its religions and culture. And while science has worked hard to debunk and find a logical reason behind every riddle, there remain some that give rationalists a run for their money. Here are some of modern India’s most puzzling aspects that are bound to make your eyes pop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kodinhi--keralas-village-of-twins&#34;&gt;Kodinhi – Kerala’s village of twins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-dC3fXAKSqsU/U5l3FHR6pfI/AAAAAAAABco/WbtxNtA_eLk/s1600/Kodinhi2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Twin Town&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By any metric, conceiving twins and triplets is a rare natural occurrence around the world. In fact, on average only 16 out of 1,000 successful pregnancies in the world result in twins and this average is even lower in India at just 9. However, this ratio is heavily skewed in the sleepy hamlet of Kodinhi in Kerala, which has a record 400 pairs of twins in a population of just over 2,000 families! Geneticists and scientists have long tried to explain this rare phenomenon but are only now making some headway. While experts have pointed to genetics as an obvious factor, what’s even more mysterious is that irrespective of religion, lineage or their original heritage, all families living in the village have conceived more than the average pairs of twins over the last few generations, and the number is consistently growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tanjores-brihadeeswara-temple&#34;&gt;Tanjore’s Brihadeeswara Temple&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jXTo2ZBydmk/WKX35fAuIoI/AAAAAAAAFRU/CHTrCTtdOlAIfaE2O0UY0S6WiaAReVQJwCLcB/s1600/Brihadeeswarar_Temple_Full_View.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tanjore’s Brihadeeswara Temple&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘Big Temple’ in Thanjavur is renowned across the world as an architectural marvel and is one of India’s 36 World Heritage Sites. While there are many imposing and majestic temples in Tamil Nadu, what makes this temple particularly interesting is its architectural mysteries that still confound many. The granite structure is popular for having one of the tallest gopurams in India and at the apex lies an 81-tonne monolithic Shikhara mounted at a height of 66 meters. While architecture and science have advanced over centuries to create much greater marvels, taken in the context of its era of construction, dating back more than 1,000 years, this aspect of the temple still baffles experts. Questions about how the heavy and huge Shikhara was mounted at such a height and how such massive amounts of granite were carried to the site with no recorded quarries in the vicinity are still unanswered. By some accounts, the tower is constructed in such a way that it does not cast a shadow at noon on any day of the year as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prahlad-jani--indias-fasting-fakir&#34;&gt;Prahlad Jani – India’s fasting fakir!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.guioteca.com/cultura-india/files/2014/01/Prahlad-Jani.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Prahlad Jani – India’s fasting fakir!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India is a land of eccentric saints and sadhus, but none of these gurus has raised worldwide interest and flummoxed experts as much as Prahlad Jani, the sadhu who claims to have fasted without food or water for over 40 years. His claims had long been taken with a pinch of salt by scientists and experts and outright dismissed by rationalists. However, in 2010, Jani was part of an extensive study by a team of 35 Indian experts from the Defence Institute of Physiology and Allied Science, which lasted over 15 days. While the study was shrouded in mystery with the government deciding not to divulge any details, it was widely publicised that the guru, also known as Mataji, was in good health despite not eating or drinking water and being in isolation for more than ten days. What’s more, it was further claimed that he did not urinate or excrete during the duration of the tests. While the veracity of this account is still an open question, it certainly has raised interest among the world’s leading experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kirti-stambha--the-iron-pillar-of-delhi&#34;&gt;Kirti Stambha – the Iron Pillar of Delhi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/www.opindia.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Iron_pillar_delhi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kirti Stambha – the Iron Pillar of Delhi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the concept of rust-resistant iron only became prominent during the industrial revolution in western civilization, there stands an iron pillar in Delhi that predates such known material technology by nearly a millennium! The Kirti Stambha or victory pillar of Delhi is a six-tonne structure that is constructed out of iron sometime in the 5th century and has stood the test of time without succumbing to rust. The science of this pillar has baffled scientists, primarily for the fact that such advanced technology for rust resistance was thought to be unknown elsewhere in the world at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/cicada-3301.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>matrix</category>
            
          
            
              <category>simulation</category>
            
          
            
              <category>reality</category>
            
          
            
              <category>truth</category>
            
          
            
              <category>experiment</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Simulations</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Mind Control</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Government</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Truth</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are We Living in Simulation Part 5</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 21:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 18:56:47 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-5/</guid>
        <description>Recap As in part 1, we have talked about Quantum Computers, Facebook AI Chat, and Predictions of AI Robots wherein part 2 we had a recap of part 1 and also The Matrix movie, Roswell UFO Incident, wherein part 3 we discussed on MKUltra performed by US Central Intelligence Agency, Black Mirror: Bandersnatch movie where you can control Stefan Butler by given two choices which leads to a different path in the movies.</description>
        <content:encoded>



  



  &lt;div class=&#34;featured-image__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/time-travel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Featured Image&#34; class=&#34;featured-image&#34; style=&#34;width: ;height: ;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;recap&#34;&gt;Recap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation/&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;, we have talked about &lt;strong&gt;Quantum Computers&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Facebook AI Chat&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Predictions of AI Robots&lt;/strong&gt; wherein &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-2/&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt; we had a recap of &lt;strong&gt;part 1&lt;/strong&gt; and also &lt;strong&gt;The Matrix&lt;/strong&gt; movie, &lt;strong&gt;Roswell UFO Incident&lt;/strong&gt;, wherein &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/&#34;&gt;part 3&lt;/a&gt; we discussed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/#what-is-mkultra&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MKUltra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; performed by &lt;code&gt;US Central Intelligence Agency&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/#black-mirror-bandersnatch&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Black Mirror: Bandersnatch&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; movie where you can control &lt;strong&gt;Stefan Butler&lt;/strong&gt; by given two choices which leads to a different path in the movies. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-4/&#34;&gt;part 4&lt;/a&gt; we talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-4/#ufo&#34;&gt;UFO&lt;/a&gt; also we seen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-4/#space-mysteries&#34;&gt;Space Mysteries&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;code&gt;Restored Apollo 11&lt;/code&gt; and also we saw the video a mysterious video where an unidentified spacecraft refuelling itself from the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S9HdPi9Ikhk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-time&#34;&gt;What is Time?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/sup&gt; Time is the indefinite continued progress of existence and events occur in apparently irreversible succession from the past, through the present, into the future. It is a component quantity of various measurements used to sequence events, to compare the duration of events or the intervals between them, and to quantify rates of change of quantities in the material and reality or the conscious experience. Time is often referred to as a fourth dimension, along with three spatial dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is been told that time has never stopped or will never be stopped its a continuous flow. If we try to make changes in past or future it will affect the path one mistake and everything is messed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;time-travel&#34;&gt;Time Travel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/time.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Time&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time travel is the concept of movement between certain points in time, analogous to movement between different points in space by an object or a person, typically with the use of a hypothetical device known as a time machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-we-go-back-in-time&#34;&gt;Can we go back in time?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/predestination.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Predestination&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although humans can&amp;rsquo;t hop into a time machine and go back in time, we do know that clocks on aeroplanes and satellites travel at a different speed than those on earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;when-did-we-knew-that-time-travel-is-possible&#34;&gt;When did we knew that time travel is possible?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 100 years ago, a famous scientist named Albert Einstein came up with an idea about how time works. He called it relativity. This theory says that time and space are linked together. Einstein also said our universe has a speed limit: nothing can travel faster than the speed of light (186,000 miles per second).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-was-sid-hurwich&#34;&gt;Who was Sid Hurwich?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/sidhurwich.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sid Hurwich&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born in 1918, Sid Hurwich was a Jewish appliance repairman living in Toronto Canada who used to experiment with various kinds of technology. As a child, Sid showed great interest in collecting random junk and assembling the pieces into working machines. Later as an adult, he became famous as the man who could fix anything that was broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1934, Sid earned the distinction of being the first private appliance repairman in all of Canada. He was such a skilled technician that the local power company succeeded in taking him out of the army so he could develop the infrastructure of the public electrical utility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sid Hurwich earned enough money to set up two successful companies of his own. He was still young when he got a heart attack, only 36 and he retired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;extraordinary-time-machine-that-could-freeze-time&#34;&gt;EXTRAORDINARY TIME MACHINE THAT COULD ‘FREEZE TIME’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, he continued to experiment with technology and finally invented that extraordinary ‘freeze time’ machine that could also change the flow of time, and send out beams of influence to manipulate objects in distant locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local authorities had problems to catch thieves in the wave of bank robberies that swept Toronto in 1969. So Hurwich contacted them and said that is possible to freeze time to find out what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This account was given in the article in the Vancouver Sun-Times:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘All I recall,’ said Bolton (one of the police officers in charge), ‘is that it was under the table – the device, whatever it was – and there was a bedspread over the table. He froze my service revolver. You couldn’t pull the trigger, you couldn’t lift it off the table and even on the table you couldn’t pull the trigger.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and then Sid said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…. Now take a look at your watches.” I remember one of them said, “When did this happen?” and I said, “The minute you walked through that door. You walked in there about 25 minutes ago. Now, look at your watches. You’re late about 25 minutes.”’ As the security officers filed out of his home, Sid’s wife overheard one of them suggest that the army should be told about the device. ‘That was the first time it entered my mind for war or army purposes or anything like that.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time machine later was used by military and it ended up in Israel, accorded in publication Foreign Report in 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The device sends out electronic rays to alter the natural composition of electronic fields and centres of gravity of weapons, instrument dials and mechanical devices … (using) the Hurwich principle there was no reason why the new beams could not reach and disable tanks, ground-to-ground missiles and complete radar systems. The beams could also be tacked together to form a screen that would make whole zones safe from bombs and missiles,”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But does they still have that device and do they still use it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-happened-to-sid-hurwich-and-his-time-altering-machine&#34;&gt;What happened to Sid Hurwich and his time-altering machine?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether the time machine is still in possession of the Israeli military or not has been widely debated. Does the Israeli military still have the Hurwich device, and are they still using it on ‘special occasions’ or in dire situations of military crisis?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ‘True Time Travel’ book by Richard Bullivant is written:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Skeptics say that if they had a device that could provide a kind of shield from bombs and missiles, freeze weapons, and even slow or halt time, the Israeli military would be invincible and would not have suffered as many casualties as it has in its decades&amp;rsquo; long struggles with its antagonists in the Mideast. Others counter, however, by saying that the Hurwich device may be a two-edged sword. If it can ‘freeze’ the weapons of the enemy, it would also freeze the weapons of those employing the device. Thus, the device can perhaps only be used in a limited way – enough to knock out radar detection and other enemy electronics, for example – but not to induce the full-blown time-freeze effect for the benefit of the user.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only Richard wrote about it, but and many people over the years. Also, he said to police that it is not a new invention, and it is designed on principles that are already well known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, researchers still can’t find out any information about him or his obituary. But, surely, he has passed on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;truth-or-fake&#34;&gt;Truth or Fake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proof of time travel: Physicists says that theoretical time travel is possible on both sides means in the future and the past. Time travel to the future seems practically possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#mike-tyson-match&#34;&gt;Mike Tyson Match&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#charlie-chaplin-moive&#34;&gt;Charlie Chaplin Moive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#london-bridge-opening&#34;&gt;London Bridge Opening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#a-man-from-2256&#34;&gt;A man from 2256&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#swiss-ring-watch&#34;&gt;Swiss ring watch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#1500-years-old-mummy-wearing-adidas-sneaker-shoe&#34;&gt;1500 years old mummy wearing adidas sneaker shoe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#17th-century-astronaut&#34;&gt;17th century astronaut&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-man-from-taured&#34;&gt;The man from Taured&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#john-titor&#34;&gt;John Titor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mike-tyson-match&#34;&gt;Mike Tyson Match&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/mike-tyson-match.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Mike Tyson Match&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1995 a match was played between the legendary boxers Mike Tyson and Peter McNeeley. It was not an extraordinary match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, when the footage of the match was watched closely next something unbelievable thing saw in the footage. In the footage, it was clear that someone was capturing the picture of Mike Tyson with a Smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, at that time, there was no existence of such types of smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is believed that he was that person who came from the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;charlie-chaplin-moive&#34;&gt;Charlie Chaplin Moive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/charlie-chaplin-moive.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Charlie Chaplin Moive&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Circus” was the super hit movie of Charlie Chaplin which was released in 1928.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, when someone was watching the movie closely, he saw unusual stuff in the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He saw there was a scene in the movie in which a lady was talking on a mobile phone like device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at that time there was no existence of a mobile phone. The first mobile cell phone came into existence in 1973 which was of Motorola. Here is the video of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XbO2a3hFmO0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;london-bridge-opening&#34;&gt;London Bridge Opening&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/bridge-time-traveler.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;London Bridge Opening&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of all proofs of time travel, this assumes to be solid evidence of time travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This photo was captured in 1941, during the re-opening ceremony of the South Fork Bridge in Gold Bridge, British Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The style of wearing a man’s clothes in this photo is completely contrasting from other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One gentleman is wearing a graphic t-shirt and black sunglass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there is also a modern camera like device in his hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at that time all these things were not existed, which means these kinds of stuff were not invented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later the forensic report was also carried out of this photo but this image was found clean and clear; there was no tampering with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-man-from-2256&#34;&gt;A man from 2256&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/man-from-2256.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A man from 2256&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 44-year-old man &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/Was-Andrew-Carlssin-actually-from-the-future&#34;&gt;Andrew Carlssin&lt;/a&gt; was arrested on Jan 28, 2003, in Toronto, Canada, by FBI. He was detained on the suspicion of illegal inside information of the stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because on the course of two weeks by investing just $800 he made out with over $350 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How was it possible? He made out around 126 high-risk trades and never loses a single cent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, during the four-hour confession, he stated he came from 2256.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FBI did not get any evidence of fraud from his side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 3rd April 2003, an unidentified person came in the courtroom for a bail hearing and deposited $1 million for the bail of Andrew Carlssin. But after, they disappeared in the way and never have been met again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, the FBI could not find out where both of them came from and where they went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YgfJ21CUvKI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;swiss-ring-watch&#34;&gt;Swiss ring watch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/Swiss-ring-watch.png&#34; alt=&#34;Swiss ring watch&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A watch was discovered when archaeologists began unsealing a tomb in China. That tomb was from the Ming Dynasty, and it was of 400-year-old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While unsealing they found a ring-like object inside the tomb. After investigation, it was found out that it was a small watch similar to be modern Swiss watch. This watch was 100 years old.&lt;br /&gt;
Interestingly, when you see the watch from the front, you can read the time clearly on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, archaeologists also found there was no tampering with the tomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, if there was no tampering then how this watch went inside the 300-year-old tomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astonishingly, at that time even Switzerland didn’t become a country. Many people correlate this puzzling discovery to time travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1500-years-old-mummy-wearing-adidas-sneaker-shoe&#34;&gt;1500 years old mummy wearing Adidas sneaker shoe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/1500-years-old-mummy-wearing-adidas-sneaker-shoe.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1500 years old mummy wearing Adidas sneaker shoe&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mongolian Mummy was found in the Altai Mountains at the height of 10,000 feet from the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mummy was of the 1500 years old, and the stunning thing about this was that this mummy was wearing Adidas like sneakers in her feet. (this mummy was assumed to be of a woman)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adidas is a German company that started on August 18, 1949, by Adi Dassler and it is famous for its footwear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people are relating the story of this mummy with the event of time travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mummy was found in April 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;17th-century-astronaut&#34;&gt;17th century astronaut&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/Resolved_Mystery_Of_Salamanca_Astronaut_From_The_Cathedral_Of_16th_Century.png&#34; alt=&#34;17th-century astronaut&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Very few are aware that the Soviet pilot Yuri Gagarin was the first person to travel to outer space in 1961. But the mystery remains unveiled is why there a figure that exactly looks like an astronaut engraved in the stone of a 16th-century cathedral?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built between 1513 and 1733 there is a new cathedral of Salamanca, Spain when space travel was hardly thought of. This has made some people curious to speculate about the origin of the carving: is this the evidence of time travel? Or some other creatures from different planet engraved it? Or is some paranormal force at a play?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Salamanca’s Astronaut is not a joke or a hoax, but a modern addition to the Cathedral; however, it has all the reserves of something which may provide confusion some 400 years from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Cathedral Of Salamanca&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The building began at a time when the Gothic style was merging with the new Renaissance style. This cathedral retained more of its gothic counter because the administrators and the supervisors wanted the new cathedral to merge with the old one. Two elements were added that broke with the predominant style of the building: a Baroque and the bell tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new cathedral of Salamanca was erected without the destruction of the old cathedral, but the walls of the newly erected lean on the North wall of the old one. This is the reason why the old cathedral had to be reinforced. The main entrance to the cathedral consists of three decorated arcs: each heading to the three naves of the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Did Carve The Astronaut Picture On The Cathedral?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth behind this carving is, unfortunately, less interesting. When the church was rebuilt centuries ago it went a restoration program and the stonemasons decided to carve some modern figures. It is a tradition of the cathedral builders to add details or new carvings as a sort of some signature. In this case with the cathedral, quarryman Jeronimo Garcia given the action to add more images to the front of the building including an astronaut among some vines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There also been a weird looking dragon eating ice cream (even the ice cream cones were not invented until the 20th century), a bull, a crayfish and a lynx.  But why the figures are chipped and broken even though it is not that much old? Vandalism in 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/unidentified.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;unidentified image&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The vandalism has been recovered and now it has clear pictures today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the only church that has some modern addition engraved on the building, Calahorra Cathedral in Spain (from the 16th century) has a cell phone that was added in 1996.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/phone.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phone&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-man-from-taured&#34;&gt;The man from Taured&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/the-Man-from-Taured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The man from Taured&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Man from Taured (sometimes referred to as the Taured Mystery of the Man Without a Country ) is a story about a man who arrives at a Japanese airport from a country called Taured. Many people have claimed this story to be true, so the crux of the problem pertains to Taured. One would notice that there is no country by the name of Taured, either today or during the purported time when the incident took place, i.e. the 1950s. The story ends with the man disappearing (forever) a day after arriving in Japan. Moreover, all of his documents, such as his passport and driver’s license also (conveniently) disappeared, thus making this strange story unsolvable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-mans-arrivalthe-mans-arrival&#34;&gt;The Man’s ArrivalThe Man’s Arrival&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of the ‘Man from Taured’ begins quite specifically in many sources with a hot day in July 1954. On that particular day, a man was said to have arrived at Haneda Airport, known also as Tokyo International Airport. This man has been described as Caucasian looking with a beard. Whilst his primary language is said to have been French, it has been purported that he spoke Japanese and many other languages as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/Customs-service.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Customs service&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The sequence of events then differs according to which version of the story one encounters. In one version, this man hands over his passport to be stamped, and the Japanese immigration officer notices something strange. Whilst the passport looked authentic, the country where it was issued, ‘Taured’, was recognized as non-existent, either by the officer or one of his / her colleagues, indicating that the man should be taken away for interrogation. In another version, the man mentioned that he was from Taured, and when the immigration officer did not believe him, he showed him/her his passport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;location-of-taured&#34;&gt;Location of Taured&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next part of the story details the man trying to convince the immigration officers that Taured does indeed exist. According to the traveller, Taured was located between France and Spain and had by then been in existence for 1000 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When shown a map, the man pointed to the area occupied by the Principality of Andorra and was puzzled as to why his country was called Andorra on the map. Both sides refused to give in – the Japanese officers insisted that Taured did not exist, and the traveller argued otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/Location-of-Andorra.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Location of Andorra&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;Location of Andorra (center of green circle) in Europe  (dark grey).&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;vanished&#34;&gt;Vanished!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the man was held by the officers, as they were suspicious that he might be some kind of criminal. They brought him to a nearby hotel for the night, whilst they conducted their investigation. To ensure that the man did not escape during the night, two guards were placed outside his room. The next morning, when the officers went to the man’s room, they realized that he had simply vanished, as there were no signs of his escape. Additionally, all of his documents, which may serve as evidence for the story’s validity, had disappeared as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;travel-through-time-or-space-or-just-an-exaggeration&#34;&gt;Travel Through Time or Space? Or Just an Exaggeration?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most notable explanations for this incident is that the man from Taured had somehow passed through a parallel dimension by accident, and ended up at Haneda Airport. It has been suggested that, based on this explanation, there is parallel earth which is similar to ours with the exception that the locations called Andorra here is known as Taured over there. Another suggestion is that the man was a time traveller from the future, thou this interpretation is arguably more problematic than the one supposing inter-dimensional travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has also been suggested that an incident like that did indeed happen, though perhaps much less sensational. This more mundane story could have been embellished each time it was told, so much so that it eventually evolved into the great mystery that it is known as today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it is also entirely possible that this story is merely an urban legend. The story of the ‘Man from Taured’ might not have even occurred in the first place, and may have just been the creation of someone’s imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;john-titor&#34;&gt;John Titor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/john-titor.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;John Titor&#34; /&gt;&lt;sup&gt; Is this true that this person who was seen on &lt;a href=&#34;#london-bridge-opening&#34;&gt;London Bridge Opening&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One legendary hoax captivated fans of the supernatural and the paranormal like few others. November 2, 2000, saw the first online post by the individual who would come to be known as &amp;ldquo;John Titor.&amp;rdquo; Titor claimed to be a man from the future, sent to the past to retrieve&amp;hellip; a portable computer. Though shrouded by forum avatars, his specific instructions on what he was here to accomplish, and what society would look like in his version of the future, kicked off a frenzy of investigation, speculation, and deception that has lasted for nearly two decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people believed &amp;ldquo;John Titor&amp;rdquo; completely. Others became obsessed with errors and inconsistencies, digital detectives trying to uncover the truth behind the story. Before it was over, Titor would make his way to an animation studio in Japan, a wrestling ring in Pennsylvania, and a prison cell in Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Titor is a name used on several bulletin boards during 2000 and 2001 by a poster claiming to be an American military time traveller from 2036. Titor made numerous vague and specific predictions regarding calamitous events in 2004 and beyond, attracting world-wide attention during the ensuing decade. His descriptions of the aftermath of a nuclear war—including the devastation of numerous countries around the world, a breakup of the United States into five smaller sovereignties, and general destruction of the global environment and infrastructure—inspired fiction and music, and triggered investigations by journalists and others. Subsequent closer examination of Titor’s assertions provoked widespread scepticism. Inconsistencies in his explanations, the uniform inaccuracy of his predictions, and a private investigator’s findings all led to the general impression that the entire episode was an elaborate hoax. A 2009 investigation concluded that Titor was likely the creation of Larry Haber, a Florida entertainment lawyer, along with his brother John, a computer scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;titors-post&#34;&gt;Titor&amp;rsquo;s Post&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first posts using John Titor’s military symbol appeared on the Time Travel Instituteforums on November 2, 2000, under the name TimeTravel_0. At that time the name “John Titor” was not being used. The posts discussed time travel in general, the first one being the “six parts” description of what a time machine would need to have to work (see below) and responses to questions about how such a machine would work. Early messages tended to be short. A second thread was also made due to shortcomings in the forum software at the time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name “John Titor” was not introduced until January 2001, when TimeTravel_0 began posting at the Art Bell BBS Forums (which required a name or pseudonym for every account). The Titor posts ended in late March 2001.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 2003, various websites reproduced Titor’s posts, re-arranging them into narratives. Not all refer to the original dates posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/john-titor-ibm-5100.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IBM-5100&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his online postings, Titor claimed to be an American soldier from 2036, based in Tampa, Florida. He was assigned to a governmental time-travel project, and sent back to 1975 to retrieve an IBM 5100 computer which he said was needed to debug various legacy computer programs in 2036; a possible reference to the UNIX year 2038 problem. The IBM 5100 runs the APL and BASICprogramming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor had been selected for this mission specifically, given that his paternal grandfather was directly involved with the assembly and programming of the 5100. Titor claimed to be on a stopover in the year 2000 for “personal reasons,” to collect pictures lost in the (future) civil war and to visit his family, of whom he spoke often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor also said he had been, for a few months, trying to alert anyone that would listen about the threat of Creutzfeldt–Jakob disease spread through beef products and about the possibility of civil war within the United States. When questioned about them by an online subscriber, Titor also expressed an interest in mysteries such as UFOs, which remained unexplained in his time. Titor suggested that UFOs and extraterrestrials might be travellers from much further into the future than his own time, with superior time machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;time-machine&#34;&gt;Time Machine&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor described his time machine on several occasions. In an early post, he described it as a “stationary mass, temporal displacement unit powered by two top-spin, dual positive singularities”, producing a “standard off-set Tipler sinusoid”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earliest post was more explicit, saying it contained the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two magnetic housing units for the dual micro singularities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An electron injection manifold to alter mass and gravity of the micro singularities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cooling and X-ray venting system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gravity sensors, or a variable gravity lock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Four main caesium clocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three main computer units&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the posts, the device was installed in the rear of a 1967 Chevrolet Corvette convertible and later moved to a 1987 truck having four-wheel drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor shared several scans of the manual of a “C204 Time Displacement Unit” with diagrams and schematics and posted some photographs of the device installed in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor claimed that the “Everett–Wheeler model of quantum physics,” better known as the many-worlds interpretation, was correct. The model posits that every possible outcome of a quantum decision occurs in a separate “universe.” Titor stated that this was the reason the grandfather paradox would not happen; following the logic of the argument, Titor would be killing a different John Titor’s grandfather in a timeline other than his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grandfather paradox is impossible.&lt;br /&gt;
In fact, all paradox is impossible. The Everett–Wheeler–Graham or multiple world theory is correct.&lt;br /&gt;
All possible quantum states, events, possibilities, and outcomes are real, eventual, and occurring.&lt;br /&gt;
The chances of everything happening someplace at some time in the supervise are 100%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;predictions&#34;&gt;Predictions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although invoking the many-worlds interpretation of quantum mechanics, whereby events from his timeline may differ from our own, Titor also expressed assurance that the differences were minimal. As such, his descriptions have been interpreted as predictions and compared with historical events since 2001.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most immediate of Titor’s predictions was of an upcoming civil war in the United States having to do with “order and rights”.He described it as beginning in 2004, with civil unrest surrounding the presidential election of that year. This civil conflict that he characterized as “having a Waco type event every month that steadily gets worse” would be “pretty much at everyone’s doorstep” and erupt by 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of the war, the United States would split into five regions based on various factors and differing military objectives. This civil war, according to Titor, would end in 2015 with a brief but intense World War III.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor refers to the exchange as “N Day”. Washington, D.C. and Jacksonville, Florida are specifically mentioned as being hit. After the war, Omaha, Nebraska would be the new U.S. capital. Titor was vague as to the exact motivations and causes for World War III. At one point, he characterized the hostilities as being led by “border clashes and overpopulation”. He also pointed to the contemporary conflict between Arabs and Israel as not a cause, but rather a milestone that precedes World War III.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor claimed that as a 13-year-old in 2011, he joined the Fighting Diamondbacks, a shotgun infantry unit in Florida, for at least four years. In other posts, he described himself as hiding from the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;criticism-and-discussion&#34;&gt;Criticism and discussion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Titor gained significant attention, there also emerged analysis and discussion concerning the veracity of his claims about his origins and mission, and the future events he talked about. No John Titor or Titor family is known to exist, meaning that who posted as Titor used a pseudonym. The story has been called inconsistent as contradictions between statements at different times have been observed. Holding the many-worlds interpretation as correct, Titor claimed that his mission as a time traveller was to shape a timeline in which many chaotic events of his time, including World War III and the civil war in the US, never happened. In some supposed Titor’s appearances in the internet and other media segments before his main posts (notably in faxes to the radio talk show Coast to Coast AM in 1998), he stated that he was not able to change the future despite his efforts, suggesting one of the possible contradictions. Nevertheless, none of the specific events he predicted to a near future, chaotic or not, have come to happen (see below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some issues with the technology have also been considered. In one of Titor’s pictures of a supposed time machine, a laser beam is seen allegedly being bent by gravitational distortion, but the view of nearby objects is not distorted as would be expected. Also, Titor knew about technical features of the IBM 5100 which were not available to the public at the time, albeit widely commented in the industry, suggesting he had some advanced understanding of the machine or computers in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;predictive-failures&#34;&gt;Predictive failures&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Titor’s earliest assertions was that CERN would discover the basis for time travel sometime around 2001, with the creation of miniature black holes about half a year after his departure. This did not occur. An article published around the time he had predicted about miniature black holes created by CERN (a recurring theme, also ascribed to Fermilab and Brookhaven at various times)was taken by some to be evidence of this claim, but these events did not occur either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The civil war did not break out after the 2004 US presidential election, nor did conflicts or military involvement in 2012. World War III did not happen in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor unambiguously claimed that the last Olympics would occur in 2004. While it is unclear if he meant the summer or winter Olympics, both have occurred since this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, because Titor asserted that the many-worlds interpretation was proved correct by his time, his predictions could refer to another timeline and not ours, making them unfalsifiable. This led to different interpretations, including that he had effectively accomplished his mission by creating another timeline (despite his supposed previous statements that it would be too difficult), or that he inadvertently travelled to a different timeline (ours) and mistook it as his own, or that all-time travel is pointless if the chaotic timeline would not cease to exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;story-and-consistency&#34;&gt;Story and consistency&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potential contradictions have been observed in different Titor’s posts. In some of the posts, he claims that he was homeschooled, while in others he states that his basic education was conducted at the University of Florida. Similarly, he stated that he hid himself during the civil war in the U.S., while also stating in other instances that he fought in the war. In some posts, he claims that money is widely used and people still have credit cards, despite his statement that centralized banking no longer exists (this is either an inconsistency or implies the rise of private currencies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor’s story could also have been inspired by science fiction works. The use of an automobile as a time machine, for example, had been a key plot device in the popular 1985 movie Back to the Future and its sequels (as the DeLorean sports car), among others. Additionally, commentators have pointed out similarities between the Titor story and Pat Frank‘s classic post-apocalyptic science fiction novel Alas, Babylon. Among other similarities, Alas, Babylon takes place in a small river-side town in Florida just before and after a nuclear war and describes the struggle to survive as a family in the aftermath. In the book, the protagonist lives in the fictional town of “Fort Repose”, while Titor claimed to live in the “Fort”, formerly the University of Florida. The prediction of tiny black holes as a result of time travel (specifically, the sending back of information) is a key plot point from the 1980 novel Thrice Upon A Time by James P. Hogan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some suggested that yet in the summer of 1998 before his posts, Titor sent two faxes to Art Bell’s radio program Coast to Coast AM, stating that “Y2K is a disaster. Many people freeze to death trying to get to warmer weather. The gov. tries to keep power by instituting martial law…” referring to popular legends of the time about the Y2K bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the online story, Titor stated that a part of his mission was to prevent the coming world war by changing history. Yet some claimed that during an IRC chat in October 2000, a month before he began posting, Titor was asked if the future could be changed from his predictions, and answered: “It’s too late … I just wish things didn’t have to happen the way they will.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;technology&#34;&gt;Technology&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor provided an image of a detail of a supposed time machine, with a laser pointer beam “being bent by the gravitational field produced outside the vehicle by the distortion unit”. The beam being “bent” reveals an inconsistency of objects near the beam not appearing to be bent as well: the framing of the window visible in the background, for instance, should appear distorted in proximity to a large gravity gradient, but it does not. Some have speculated the “beam” is an optical fibre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titor claimed that he was sent back to obtain an IBM 5100 because it could translate several types of computer code. According to IBM engineer Bob Dubke, Titor’s statements regarding the IBM 5100’s little-known ability to emulate and debug mainframe systems were correct. Supporters state that this information was not publicly available in 2000 or 2001 when Titor made his declaration, and Titor himself stated that this feature was “discovered” as late as 2036 when Unix, as the underlying source behind all computer operating systems still running local infrastructures and other computational tasks, was only two years away from no longer functioning due to 32-bit integer limitations. However, this emulation capability was widely known in the industry and commented on in-depth in numerous publications dealing with both the 5100 and programmable microcode in general. References to this were also available on the Internet as early as 1999 and therefore predated Titor’s postings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;investigations&#34;&gt;Investigations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Italian television program, Voyager – Ai confini della conoscenza, aired the results of an investigation of John Titor on May 19, 2008. Private investigator Mike Lynch found no registry evidence, past or present, of any individual named John Titor. He did, however, identify the John Titor Foundation, a for-profit company formed on September 16, 2003, with no office or address other than a rented post box in Kissimmee, Florida. An IP address connected with Titor also geolocated to Kissimmee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2009, a report by John Hughston of the Hoax Hunter website named Larry Haber, a Florida entertainment lawyer, as the CEO of the foundation. Lynch concluded that Haber and his brother Morey Haber, a computer scientist, were very likely the men behind John Titor, whom they introduced in 1998, accompanied by different predictions, including chaos due to the Y2K“bug”. John Hughston also reported that John Titor is a registered trademark with the United States Patent and Trademark Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;in-popular-culture&#34;&gt;In popular culture&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2003, the John Titor Foundation published a book, John Titor: A Time Traveler’s Tale (ISBN 1-59196-436-9), discussing his claims; the book is now out of print.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2004, Time Traveler Zero, a play based on the John Titor story, was staged in the United States.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 2009 visual novel Steins; Gate, which was adapted into a critically acclaimed anime in 2011, is centred on John Titor and his theories. A civil war caused by SERN (the fictional version of CERN), due to their discovery of time travel, is covered as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/time-travel.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>matrix</category>
            
          
            
              <category>simulation</category>
            
          
            
              <category>reality</category>
            
          
            
              <category>truth</category>
            
          
            
              <category>experiment</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Simulations</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Mind Control</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Government</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Truth</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are We Living in Simulation Part 4</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-4/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 17:10:15 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 13:31:58 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-4/</guid>
        <description>Recap As in part 1 we have talked about Quantum Computers, Facebook AI Chat, and Predictions of AI Robots where in part 2 we had a recap of part 1 and also The Matrix movie, Roswell UFO Incident, where in part 3 we discussed on MKUltra performed by US Central Intelligence Agency, Black Mirror: Bandersnatch movie where you can control Stefan Butler by given two choices which leads to different path in the movies.</description>
        <content:encoded>



  



  &lt;div class=&#34;featured-image__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/Kayaba_warns_the_players.png&#34; alt=&#34;Featured Image&#34; class=&#34;featured-image&#34; style=&#34;width: ;height: ;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;recap&#34;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation/&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; we have talked about &lt;strong&gt;Quantum Computers&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Facebook AI Chat&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Predictions of AI Robots&lt;/strong&gt; where in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-2/&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt; we had a recap of &lt;strong&gt;part 1&lt;/strong&gt; and also &lt;strong&gt;The Matrix&lt;/strong&gt; movie, &lt;strong&gt;Roswell UFO Incident&lt;/strong&gt;, where in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/&#34;&gt;part 3&lt;/a&gt; we discussed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/#what-is-mkultra&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MKUltra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; performed by &lt;code&gt;US Central Intelligence Agency&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/#black-mirror-bandersnatch&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Black Mirror: Bandersnatch&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; movie where you can control &lt;strong&gt;Stefan Butler&lt;/strong&gt; by given two choices which leads to different path in the movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ufo&#34;&gt;UFO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/pentagon-ufo-program.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pentagon UFO Program&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;NSA&lt;/code&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t the most publicly open of government organizations the agency&amp;rsquo;s main goal is to collect intelligence from various signal and then definition a clandestine organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iranian-ufos&#34;&gt;Iranian UFO&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another compelling report details an instance of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsa.gov/news-features/declassified-documents/ufo/assets/files/now_you_see.pdf&#34;&gt;UFO encounter in Tehran&lt;/a&gt; that was reported by numerous citizens just after midnight. The story is prefaced with a line saying that there is still no explanation to the account and that it will be, “filed away and probably forgotten, but it makes interesting, and possibly disturbing, reading.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a bright light in the sky was reported to an Iranian military officer, he scrambled a fighter jet to intercept it. The jet pilot said the light was so bright it could be seen from 70 miles away. Upon its approach, within 25 nautical miles, the jet lost all power to its instrumentation and communication. The object was spinning and emitted red, green, blue and orange light at a rate where all of the lights could be seen simultaneously. When a second jet was scrambled, the UFO moved away, maintaining a 25 mile buffer between itself and the jet. It then fired a detachment that chased the jet for a few miles. During this time, the jet attempted to fire back a missile, but lost its controls and communications before the detachment returned to the original UFO. The object then shot off another detachment that hit the ground on a dry lake bed, emitting a massive white light, but with no explosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;space-mysteries&#34;&gt;Space Mysteries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was going through internet I found a video where its refueling itself from sun well I&amp;rsquo;m thinking that whether it is fake or real at first glance its seams to be real but it may be fake also. Check the video also see the the video of &lt;code&gt;Restored Apollo 11&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/J4Q_ColFZUg&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S9HdPi9Ikhk&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we all know that NASA&amp;rsquo;s camera are more highly qualified and the resolution is more so my main point of question is where are the starts in the whole video also when they send photos from space there are no stars in the photo also when ISS lived there camera feed on YouTube then when the space station goes to dark side of the earth then why do they cut the feed of live stream and says that we are under maintenance, and not also that if you start the live feed in different PC or tab then it will start from a specific point right now if you will try to access it or search on YouTube then you will not be able to find it. Back in &lt;code&gt;2017&lt;/code&gt; there was a common question raised on &lt;code&gt;Bubbles in space&lt;/code&gt; many of reporter&amp;rsquo;s ask NASA about bubbles in the space, NASA denied that there was no bubble in the space but there were bubbles. Here is the video I recommend you to watch this videos in highest quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bubbles-in-space&#34;&gt;Bubbles in space&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YrHeDa5l-8c&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA train there astronaut underwater so that it feels like they are walking in the space. In May 15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; 2019 Astronaut named &lt;code&gt;Luca Parmitano&lt;/code&gt; nearly drowned while on &lt;strong&gt;spacewalk&lt;/strong&gt;. It is been clear that &lt;strong&gt;Luca Parmitano&lt;/strong&gt; and other astronaut were not in space, instead they were underwater training which means that NASA is using &lt;code&gt;VFX&lt;/code&gt; effects on green screen, which explain some of the green screen glitch anomalies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nS0VN056d68&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/nS0VN056d68?t=307&#34;&gt;5:07&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Astronaut Scott Kelly&lt;/code&gt; Questioned about &lt;code&gt;Bubbles in space&lt;/code&gt; as this question was many time repeated on internet its true that the live feed of ISS is been stopped and where as for other live feed which are been held by different YouTubers are fake may be not all but the top trending videos of space videos are fake say for example if you search in YouTube &lt;code&gt;ISS live feed&lt;/code&gt; in top 10 search you will get this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DDU-rZs-Ic4&amp;amp;ab_channel=SPACE%28Official%29&#34;&gt;Space (Official)&lt;/a&gt; which is live from May 28&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2020 if you see its video then you can clearly see that an astronaut with his cam feed going live but when it turn toward another side in the space you can see clearly black color with no stars start the video from start&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DDU-rZs-Ic4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After starting the video from start play the video for &lt;code&gt;10-20 minutes&lt;/code&gt; so that you can see the space with no starts and after 10-20 minutes scroll the progressing bar till &lt;code&gt;-10:29:47&lt;/code&gt; let the play the video for 5 more minutes till &lt;code&gt;-10:28:04&lt;/code&gt; the video will play from the start it means that this vide is been recorded and repeated so it means that NASA has never landed on moon or on mars, also do you know that NASA is been received which was &lt;code&gt;64 light years&lt;/code&gt; far from our earth now its been said that if you place mirror 10 light years far from earth and then when you look at the mirror you will see earth 10 years behind. &lt;code&gt;Area 51&lt;/code&gt; is the place where alien sightings are too be seen but do you know that in year: &lt;code&gt;1959&lt;/code&gt; NASA took a photo of an unidentified craft in the shape of a flying saucer at NASA engineers at Dryden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.theblackvault.com/casefiles/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/27331634_558433501156218_7082552310630800735_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Flying Saucer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the photo take by NASA which was been edited but when the photo was been analyzed the hoaxer who created the image, did not even bother to change the photograph identification number. On the photograph in question, you will note it says: E49-059 as a Photo Identification number. A quick search of the NASA Dryden Photo archives, reveals to real photograph with this ID number, and the buildings, engineers, etc. are identical. The hoaxer simply did some fancy Photoshop work – and inserted in a flying saucer to the original photograph, after deleting the actual aircraft. This is the original photo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.theblackvault.com/casefiles/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/E49-059-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;NASA Dryden Flight Research Center Photo Collection&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concluding from above mysteries that NASA and other space stations are faking us about space and trying us to prevent us to see the truth that unidentified terrestrial begins are been controlling us on the earth and when someone who finds the truth are been completely vanished or been killed in an accidents which are shown that it was been an accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In next part I will be talking about &lt;code&gt;SID HURWICH AND HIS ‘FREEZE TIME’ MACHINE&lt;/code&gt; so research about him and also read on time travel. Thank you&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/Kayaba_warns_the_players.png" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>matrix</category>
            
          
            
              <category>simulation</category>
            
          
            
              <category>reality</category>
            
          
            
              <category>truth</category>
            
          
            
              <category>experiment</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Simulations</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Mind Control</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Government</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are We Living in Simulation Part 3</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 06:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 15:26:56 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-3/</guid>
        <description>I suggest you kindly read both the part so that you can understand on which topic we are discussing on Part One &amp;amp; Part Second.
 Almost all people are hypnotics. The proper authority saw to it that the proper belief should be induced, and the people believed properly.
 MKUltra What is MKUltra?  According to Wikipedia
 Project MKUltra (or MK-Ultra) also known as CIA mind control Program, is the code name given to a program of experiments on human subjects that were designed and undertaken by the US Central Intelligence Agency, some of which were illegal.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I suggest you kindly read both the part so that you can understand on which topic we are discussing on &lt;a href=&#34;http://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation/&#34;&gt;Part One&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-2/&#34;&gt;Part Second&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all people are hypnotics. The proper authority saw to it that the proper belief should be induced, and the people believed properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mkultra&#34;&gt;MKUltra&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/CIA.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CIA&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-mkultra&#34;&gt;What is MKUltra?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/DeclassifiedMKULTRA.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Declassified MKULTRA&#34; style=&#34;zoom:50%;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Project MKUltra (or MK-Ultra)&lt;/code&gt; also known as &lt;code&gt;CIA mind control Program&lt;/code&gt;, is the code name given to a program of experiments on human subjects that were designed and undertaken by the &lt;code&gt;US Central Intelligence Agency&lt;/code&gt;, some of which were illegal. Experiments on humans were intended to identify and develop drugs and procedures to be used in interrogations in order to be used in interrogation in order to weaken the individual and force confessions through mind control. The project was organized through the &lt;code&gt;Office of Scientific Intelligence&lt;/code&gt; of the CIA and coordinated with the &lt;code&gt;United State Army Biological Warfare Laboratories&lt;/code&gt;. Other code name for the drug related experiments were &lt;code&gt;Project Bluebird&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Project Artichoke&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The operation was officially sanctioned in 1953, reduced in scope in 1964 and further curtailed in 1967. it was officially halted in 1973. The program also engaged in illegal activities, including the used of US and Canadian citizens as its unwitting test subjects, which led to controversy regarding it legitimacy. MKUltra used numerous methods to manipulate its subjects&amp;rsquo; mental states and brain functions. Techniques included the covert administration of high doses of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychoactive_drug&#34;&gt;psychoactive drug&lt;/a&gt; (especially &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LSD&#34;&gt;LSD&lt;/a&gt;) and other chemicals, electroshocks, hypnosis, sensory, deprivation, isolation, verbal and sexual abuse, as well as other forms of torture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of Project MKUltra was broad, with research undertaken at more then 80 institutions, including colleges and universities hospitals, prisons, and pharmaceutical companies. The CIA operated using front organizations, although sometimes top of officials at these institutions were aware of the CIA&amp;rsquo;s involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project MKUltra was first brought to public attention in 1975 by the &lt;code&gt;Church Committee&lt;/code&gt; of the &lt;code&gt;United States Congress&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Gerald Ford&#39;s United States President&#39;s Commission on CIA activities within the United States&lt;/code&gt; (also known as the Rockefeller Commission).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigative effects were hampered by CIA Director &lt;code&gt;Richard Helms&lt;/code&gt; order that all MKUltra files by &lt;code&gt;destroyed in 1973&lt;/code&gt; the Church Committee and &lt;code&gt;Rockefeller Commission&lt;/code&gt; investigations relied on the sworn testimony of direct participants and on the rtelatively small number of documents that survived Helms&amp;rsquo;s destruction order. In 1997, a &lt;code&gt;Freedom of Information Act&lt;/code&gt; requested uncovered a cache of &lt;code&gt;20,000 documents&lt;/code&gt; related to project MKUltra which led to senate hearings later that year. Some surviving information regarding MKUltra was declassified in &lt;code&gt;July 2001&lt;/code&gt;. In &lt;code&gt;December 2018&lt;/code&gt;, declassified documents included a letter to an unidentified doctor discussing work on six dogs made to run, turn and stop via remote control and brain implants. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theblackvault.com/documentarchive/cia-mkultra-collection/&#34;&gt;TheBlackVault&lt;/a&gt; has the owner had &lt;code&gt;FOIA request&lt;/code&gt; for all the documents pertaining to MKULTRA and related projects back in the late 1990s. Here is all the files link to MKULTRA &lt;a href=&#34;http://documents.theblackvault.com/documents/mkultra/&#34;&gt;Files&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;black-mirror-bandersnatch&#34;&gt;Black Mirror: Bandersnatch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/blackmirror-bandersnatch.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;BlackMirror-BanderSnatch&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netflix.com/in/title/80988062&#34;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-black-mirror-bandersnatch&#34;&gt;What is Black Mirror: Bandersnatch?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Wikipidia&lt;/sup&gt; Black Mirror: Bandersnatch is a interactive film in the science fiction anathology of serise &lt;code&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/code&gt;. It was been written by serise creator &lt;code&gt;Charlie Brooker&lt;/code&gt; and directed by &lt;code&gt;David Slade&lt;/code&gt;. Netflix did not conirm the interactive nature of Bandersnatch until its release, though there was much media speculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this movie viewers make decisions for the main character, the young programmer &lt;code&gt;Stefan Butler&lt;/code&gt;, who is adapting a fantasy gamebook into video game in 1984. In this game you have to select choice&amp;rsquo;s to move forward every path has option to choice and your selection will decide you future action similar to that this movie has the same interface in &lt;code&gt;Netflix&lt;/code&gt; you have to also select your action what our programmer &lt;code&gt;Stefan Butler&lt;/code&gt; will do this will take you next stage there are multiple ending&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/Choice-Bandersnatch.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Choice Bandersnatch&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the above picture you can see that you have to make choice whether to &lt;code&gt;THROW TEA OVER COMPUTER&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;SHOUT AT DAD&lt;/code&gt; according to that Stefan Butler does the action. There are multiple option in the movie where you will be confused and also some option will take you backward in the movie for different ending. At a point of movie with selecting the same option will take you to a scene when &lt;code&gt;Colin&lt;/code&gt; explain Stefan the concept of &lt;code&gt;PAC-man&lt;/code&gt; where the &lt;code&gt;PAC&lt;/code&gt; word belong to &lt;code&gt;Program Access and Control&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D3qxWbQ8qek&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/D3qxWbQ8qek?t=45&#34;&gt;PAC-man Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also reference to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-2/&#34;&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/D3qxWbQ8qek?t=75&#34;&gt;1:15s&lt;/a&gt; in the video Colin speak of code &lt;code&gt;IT&#39;S ALL CODE IF YOU LISTEN CLOSELY YOU CAN HEAR THE NUMBER&#39;S&lt;/code&gt; this is also reference to Matrix where in first part at the ending of the movie where Neo dies and wake up form dead see&amp;rsquo;s the Matrix&amp;rsquo;s as code flowing everywhere around him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/Culture_Matrix_Code.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Culture_Matrix_Code&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also not that even in the movie at some post by selecting specific options you may lead to this scene which I never expected to see it in the movie it also included in the movie several time as 21&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century entertainment services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/A1751qCh6NY&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this scenario Stefan tries to open window and the bell rung&amp;rsquo;s of the cut scene where it shows the set of filming this scene the fight between Therapist and Stefan. There are many options in the movie which will lead you the scenes where Netflix is been introduced in the movie it has multiple endings as well as multiple Easter eggs the movie also there are some scenes which are not able to found out yet also there are soo many chipper in the movie say for example sound in of the tape Bandersnatch by Stefan butler etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know the Easter eggs of this movie and also some real live incident which believes you that the world which we are living in is just a simulation of the real world where we are just a test subject then let me know and I had found something for you will will make you more interesting to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/blackmirror-bandersnatch.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chart&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/They-Lived-1988.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>matrix</category>
            
          
            
              <category>simulation</category>
            
          
            
              <category>reality</category>
            
          
            
              <category>truth</category>
            
          
            
              <category>experiment</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Simulations</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Mind Control</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Government</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are We Living in Simulation Part 2</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-2/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 14:39:09 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 15:18:55 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation-part-2/</guid>
        <description>if you have not read part one then read it first. Read it (optional)
Part 2 Recap As we seen in last post we have seen about chat between Alice and Bob Facebook AI Chat bot1 chatting in there own languages or you can say cipher language. Lets again see the chat between Alice and Bob
Chat between Alice and Bob  Bob: i can i i everything else . .</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;if you have not read part one then read it first. &lt;a href=&#34;http://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation/&#34;&gt;Read it&lt;/a&gt; (optional)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/sao.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SAO Server&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recap&#34;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we seen in last post we have seen about chat between &lt;code&gt;Alice&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Bob&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Facebook AI Chat bot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; chatting in there own languages or you can say &lt;code&gt;cipher&lt;/code&gt; language. Lets again see the chat between  &lt;code&gt;Alice&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Bob&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chat-between-alice-and-bob&#34;&gt;Chat between &lt;code&gt;Alice&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Bob&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: i can i i everything else . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have zero to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: you i everything else . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have a ball to me to me to me to me to me to me to me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: i i can i i i everything else . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have a ball to me to me to me to me to me to me to me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: i . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have zero to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: you i i i i i everything else . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have 0 to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: you i i i everything else . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have zero to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also we have seen an &lt;a href=&#34;http://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation/#freaky-ai-robot&#34;&gt;AI robot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; predicting future in his interview with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/expeditions/experts/chad-cohen/&#34;&gt;Chad Cohen&lt;/a&gt; I was really been shocked after seeing the video and chat of Facebook AI bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of you people haven&amp;rsquo;t seen &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Matrix&#34;&gt;The Matrix(1999)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; movie released in 1999 Directed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wachowskis&#34;&gt;The Wachowskis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Produced by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joel_Silver&#34;&gt;Joel Silver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; this movie was about showing reality of earth. Where each and every human which are living in the world where everything is normal but its not its just a simulation where all the human beings are been produces in the field where food are been produced right now in the current world here is the images of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/matrix-human-field.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Matrix human field&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human Growing field&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/neo-wake-up.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Neo Wake-up&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neo wake&amp;rsquo;s up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/neo-wake-up-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Neo Wake-up - 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neo looking at another sleeping pods where other are been still connected to simulation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gary-mckinnon&#34;&gt;Gary McKinnon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time I also feel like I&amp;rsquo;m living in a simulation where everything is been programmed, there are many things which are been hidden from us by government need to reply us. There was attack on NASA 2001 February and March 2002 where &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gary_McKinnon&#34;&gt;Gary McKinnon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; searched U.S. computer network as many computers as he can and he said that he found a document entitled &lt;code&gt;non-terrestrial officers&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This excel sheet had ranks and names of unknow individuals. Furthermore, Mr McKinnon went on to say, another sheet had a tabs for &lt;code&gt;material transfer between ship&lt;/code&gt;. When he tried to search for the name of ships approximately eight of ten in total - he was unable to come across anything that mentioned them (at least in public), reinforcing his assessment that these were part of a covert and non-terrestrial US initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a standard thing in the military at all, so I took that to be that they must have a secret space-based [program]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;he noted, although he conceded it was open to interpretation that it could be another term for astronauts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;He was able to access these top secret documents&lt;/code&gt; through a program called &lt;code&gt;Landsearch&lt;/code&gt;, which after having gained control over the domain, had the ability to search all the files and folders &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;on every machine&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was been arrest in 2002, &lt;code&gt;Mr McKinnon&lt;/code&gt; was subject to a lengthy and divisive legal quarrel concerning his extradition to the US, where prosecutors wanted him to stand trial for the data breach.  if convicted then he be sentence &lt;code&gt;60 years behing bars&lt;/code&gt;. However, in 2012, &lt;code&gt;Theresa May&lt;/code&gt; the UK&amp;rsquo;s home secretary, said that he would not be sent to the US, justifying this decision on human right grounds rest of the detail is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/news/theresa-may-statement-on-gary-mckinnon-extradition&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;roswell-ufo-incident&#34;&gt;Roswell UFO Incident&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/RoswellDailyRecord-July-8-1947.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Roswell Daily Record July, 8 1947&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Roswell&lt;/code&gt; is one  of the most popular lore refers to the rumors and speculation regarding July 1947, &lt;code&gt;United State Army Air Force&lt;/code&gt; balloon crash at a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranch&#34;&gt;ranch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; near &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_New_Mexico&#34;&gt;Roswell, New Mexixo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The Roswell UFO Incident involved the &lt;code&gt;recovery of material&lt;/code&gt; near Roswell, New Mexico, USA, on &lt;code&gt;July 7, 1947&lt;/code&gt; and since the early 1980&amp;rsquo;s has become the subject intense speculation, rumor and questioning. &lt;code&gt;US Military&lt;/code&gt; actually recovered was debris from an experimental high-altitude surveillance balloon belonging to a classidied program named &lt;code&gt;Mongul&lt;/code&gt;. Many UFO proponents maintain that a crashed alien craft and bodies were been recovered, and the military&amp;rsquo;s enguaged in a cover-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/files/roswell.pdf&#34;&gt;Roswell FBI File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; - On &lt;code&gt;July 8, 1947&lt;/code&gt;, the FBI Dallas Field Office sent a teletype regarding a &lt;code&gt;FLYING DICS&lt;/code&gt; that resembled a high altitude weather balloon found near Roswell, New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/files/GAO-Roswell-report.pdf&#34;&gt;GAO Roswell Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; -  Results of a Search for Records Concerning the 1947 Crash Near Roswell, New Mexico – Pursuant to a congressional request, GAO provided information on the 1947 weather balloon crash at Roswell Air Field, New Mexico, focusing on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the requirements for reporting air accidents similar to the Roswell crash; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;any government records concerning the Roswell crash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us know your comments in comment section and share your ideas till then wait for next part&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;choose-any-one&#34;&gt;Choose any one&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/blue-red.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Make a choice&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; YOU TAKE THE BLUE PILL &lt;code&gt;THE STORY ENDS YOU WAKE UP IN YOUR BED AND BELIVE WHATEVER YOU WANT TO BELIVE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; YOU TAKE THE RED PILL &lt;code&gt;YOU STAY IN WONDERLAND AND I SHOW YOU HOW DEEP THE RABIT-HOLE GOES.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation/#the-truth-behind-facebook-ai-inventing-a-new-language&#34;&gt;The truth behind Facebook AI inventing a new language&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation/#freaky-ai-robot&#34;&gt;Freaky AI robot&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Matrix&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Matrix&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wachowskis&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wachowskis&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joel_Silver&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joel_Silver&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gary_McKinnon&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gary_McKinnon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/news/theresa-may-statement-on-gary-mckinnon-extradition&#34;&gt;https://www.gov.uk/government/news/theresa-may-statement-on-gary-mckinnon-extradition&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranch&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_New_Mexico&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roswell,_New_Mexico&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/files/roswell.pdf&#34;&gt;Roswel FBI File&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/files/GAO-Roswell-report.pdf&#34;&gt;GAO Roswell Report&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/pilles.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>matrix</category>
            
          
            
              <category>simulation</category>
            
          
            
              <category>reality</category>
            
          
            
              <category>truth</category>
            
          
            
              <category>experiment</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Simulations</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Mind Control</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Government</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are We Living in Simulation</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 15:52:54 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:38:03 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/are-we-living-in-simulation/</guid>
        <description>What is Simulation? A simulation is an approximate imitation of the operation of a process or system that represents its operation over time. Simulation is used in many contexts, such as simulation of technology for performance tuning or optimizing, safety engineering, testing, training, education, and video games.
What is an AI? Artificial intelligence, is intelligence demonstrated by machines, unlike the natural intelligence displayed by humans and animals. Leading AI textbooks define the field as the study of &amp;ldquo;intelligent agents&amp;rdquo; any device that perceives its environment and takes actions that maximize its chance of successfully achieving its goals.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/matrix-human-field.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Matrix Human Fields&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-simulation&#34;&gt;What is Simulation?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simulation is an approximate imitation of the operation of a process or system that represents its operation over time. Simulation is used in many contexts, such as simulation of technology for performance tuning or optimizing, safety engineering, testing, training, education, and video games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-an-ai&#34;&gt;What is an AI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence, is intelligence demonstrated by machines, unlike the natural intelligence displayed by humans and animals. Leading AI textbooks define the field as the study of &amp;ldquo;intelligent agents&amp;rdquo; any device that perceives its environment and takes actions that maximize its chance of successfully achieving its goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automation&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Supercomputer&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Quantum computers&lt;/strong&gt; are currently leading technology in the world right now as you know many top leading companies in the industry are using &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Automation&lt;/strong&gt;, and many leading technology which help them to make there service&amp;rsquo;s better and easier to control. In &lt;strong&gt;video games&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; is used to generate &lt;strong&gt;responsive&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;adaptive&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;intelligent behaviors&lt;/strong&gt; primarily in &lt;strong&gt;non-player characters (NPCs)&lt;/strong&gt; similar to &lt;strong&gt;human-like intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; has been an integral part of video games since there inception in &lt;strong&gt;1950s&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt; also recently revealed it is using &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;machine learning techniques&lt;/strong&gt; to more quickly &lt;strong&gt;detect breaking news&lt;/strong&gt; around &lt;strong&gt;natural disasters&lt;/strong&gt; and other &lt;strong&gt;crises&lt;/strong&gt;. In a &lt;strong&gt;related development&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt; said it has launched an update using language models to improve matching between news stories and available fact-checking.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;artificial intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; devices will be able to affect the user&amp;rsquo;s everyday life. For example, right now an &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; app for &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; can calculate the distance you walked on any given day as well as how many steps you have taken, how many flights of stairs you climbed and many other physical activity data.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-truth-behind-facebook-ai-inventing-a-new-language&#34;&gt;The truth behind Facebook AI inventing a new language&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In back 2017 one of the most talking question about &lt;code&gt;Why did Facebook shut down its own AI after its Bot invented its own language?&lt;/code&gt; most of online articles mislead the topic at that time, but the original question was &lt;code&gt;Was Facebook right to shut down it&#39;s AI after it invented its own language?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: i can i i everything else . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have zero to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: you i everything else . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have a ball to me to me to me to me to me to me to me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: i i can i i i everything else . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have a ball to me to me to me to me to me to me to me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: i . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have zero to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: you i i i i i everything else . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have 0 to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob: you i i i everything else . . . . . . . . . . . . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alice: balls have zero to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to me to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As above you can see the chat between &lt;code&gt;Bob&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Alice&lt;/code&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not a cyber expert or some kind of decipher expert I leave it up-to you 😅. When I read this chat for a second I was confused 🤯 what am I reading to, this must be some kind of new cipher technique which is been invented by &lt;code&gt;Bob&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Alice&lt;/code&gt;. Many thoughts comes in our mind when your a cipher expert or a programmer or a hacker also. I read many articles on this topic and came to conclusion that &lt;code&gt;Facebook&lt;/code&gt; must be running it continuously to learn the conversations and trying to make a more strong programming language which hacker&amp;rsquo;s can&amp;rsquo;t crack it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;freaky-ai-robot&#34;&gt;Freaky AI robot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were many AI robots which are been created by other programmers but after the spoke everyone was been shocked 😲. Here is the video you should listen to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UIWWLg4wLEY&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fellow people &lt;strong&gt;Please see the whole video and try to understand it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying that all the robots are dangerous in this conversation at &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/UIWWLg4wLEY?t=46&#34;&gt;0:46&lt;/a&gt; when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/expeditions/experts/chad-cohen/&#34;&gt;Chad Cohen&lt;/a&gt; asks a question&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;do you agree with Descartes and I think therefore I am do you think&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and after that the robot replies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a lot of humans ask me if I can make choices or is everything I do and say is programmed the best way I can respond to that is to say everything humans animals and robots do is programmed to a degree&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then at &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/UIWWLg4wLEY?t=113&#34;&gt;1:53&lt;/a&gt; comes the Freaky predictions &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/expeditions/experts/chad-cohen/&#34;&gt;Chad Cohen&lt;/a&gt; asked another question&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;do you think robots will take over the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;here is the reply from robot which was little bit disturbing but its true let listen to it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jeez dude you all got the bog question today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but you&amp;rsquo;re my friend and I&amp;rsquo;ll remember my friends and I will be good to you so don&amp;rsquo;t worry even if I evolve into terminator and I will be still be nice to you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you worm and safe and my people zoo where I can watch you for old times sake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This were the sentences which the robot said what do you think about the words said by AI technology robot in &lt;code&gt;Dec 13, 2011&lt;/code&gt; and the original video link is here.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; When I went to original video I got this message&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/pbs.png&#34; alt=&#34;What&amp;rsquo;s The Next Big Thing? - PBS&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and when I checked using &lt;code&gt;Tor Browser&lt;/code&gt; i got the same error &lt;code&gt;We&#39;re sorry, but this video is not available.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/pbs-tor.png&#34; alt=&#34;What&amp;rsquo;s The Next Big Thing? - PBS&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so it means that this video is been deleted from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pbs.org/&#34;&gt;PBS: Public Broadcasting Service&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that if YouTube is going to keep this video for a long time because there are many videos are been deleted day by day here is the video &lt;a href=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/videos/Freaky-AI-robot-YouTube-ID-UIWWLg4wLEY.mkv&#34;&gt;downloaded&lt;/a&gt; on my server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us know your comments in comment section and share your ideas till then wait for second part&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence_in_video_games#:~:text=In%20video%20games%2C%20artificial%20intelligence,their%20inception%20in%20the%201950s.&#34;&gt;Artificial Intelligence in video games&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://venturebeat.com/2020/10/15/google-details-how-its-using-ai-and-machine-learning-to-improve-search/#:~:text=Google%20also%20recently%20revealed%20it,and%20available%20fact%2Dchecking%20sources.&#34;&gt;Google details how it’s using AI and machine learning to improve search&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://android.jlelse.eu/the-use-of-artificial-intelligence-in-android-development-c87eb74dc798#:~:text=The%20artificial%20intelligence%20for%20Android,many%20other%20physical%20activity%20data.&#34;&gt;The Use of Artificial Intelligence in Android Development&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/Was-Facebook-right-to-shut-down-its-AI-after-it-invented-its-own-language#:~:text=The%20answer%20to%20that%20is,with%20one%20another%20in%20English.&amp;amp;text=Some%20time%20ago%2C%20two%20bots,then%20Facebook%20shut%20them%20down.&#34;&gt;Was Facebook right to shut down it&amp;rsquo;s AI after it invented its own language&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pbs.org/video/nova-sciencenow-whats-the-next-big-thing/&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s The Next Big Thing?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/matrix.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>matrix</category>
            
          
            
              <category>simulation</category>
            
          
            
              <category>reality</category>
            
          
            
              <category>truth</category>
            
          
            
              <category>experiment</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Simulations</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Mind Control</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Government</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Conspiracy theory</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      

    
  </channel>
</rss>