<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" 
  xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacking on Mistry Siddh - Get weakly news related to different kinds of news, tips, tricks, etc. If you have your own theory or story then comment down in the post.</title>
    <link>/series/hacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hacking on Mistry Siddh - Get weakly news related to different kinds of news, tips, tricks, etc. If you have your own theory or story then comment down in the post.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><hosted>Netlify -- netlify.com</hosted>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 14:17:46 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    
        <atom:link href="/series/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    

      
      <item>
        <title>Raspberry Pi NAS System</title>
        <link>/raspberrypi-nas/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 14:17:46 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 22:27:42 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>/raspberrypi-nas/</guid>
        <description>Overview We will be seeing a fully functional NAS server on Raspberry Pi(all pi version) homemade with simple few lines of command and with one software require before we start we will be requiring a few things before we start.
Requirments  Laptop or Desktop Stable internet connection(Mobile or Router no matter which connection is it) Raspberry Pi with 4GB+ ram (mine is Raspberry Pi 4 B+ model with 8GB of ram) MicroSD card with a minimum of 8GB size Power supply (power bank or cell phone adaptor) MicroB to HDMI with monitor(optional) if you&amp;rsquo;re going to use a monitor then you will be needing of keyboard And most important thing a cup of coffee  Step 1 Hardware setup Ok first of all we need some software which will help us to flash memory card so that we can install os in the memory card to boot in pi.</description>
        <content:encoded>



  



  &lt;div class=&#34;featured-image__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Jc4Y2jA4Yeg/maxresdefault.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Featured Image&#34; class=&#34;featured-image&#34; style=&#34;width: ;height: ;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be seeing a fully functional NAS server on Raspberry Pi(all pi version) homemade with simple few lines of command and with one software require before we start we will be requiring a few things before we start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirments&#34;&gt;Requirments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laptop or Desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable internet connection(Mobile or Router no matter which connection is it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi with 4GB+ ram (mine is Raspberry Pi 4 B+ model with 8GB of ram)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MicroSD card with a minimum of 8GB size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power supply (power bank or cell phone adaptor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MicroB to HDMI with monitor(optional) if you&amp;rsquo;re going to use a monitor then you will be needing of keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And most important thing a cup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-hardware-setup&#34;&gt;Step 1 Hardware setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok first of all we need some software which will help us to flash memory card so that we can install os in the memory card to boot in pi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberry-pi.png&#34; alt=&#34;Raspberry pi software&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/software/&#34;&gt;https://www.raspberrypi.com/software/&lt;/a&gt; and download software according to your OS I&amp;rsquo;m using Zorin OS which is based on Ubuntu so I will be using the terminal. If you are using terminal use the following command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt install rpi-imager
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;as you can see in the below image I have already installed it on my device&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/terminal-pi.png&#34; alt=&#34;Terminal&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and open it up after opening it up plugin your 8GB or higher sd card on your laptop. as you can see in the image I have inserted 8GB of card&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/disk-pi.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now do the following steps as soon in the photo&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-software.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-software1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Select &lt;strong&gt;Raspberry Pi OS(other)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-software2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Then select &lt;strong&gt;Raspberry Pi OS Lite (Legacy)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-software3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now select your disk but before writing your os we will configure it first so that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to connect any kind of ethernet cable or mini Wi-Fi. Press &lt;code&gt;ALT + SHIFT + X&lt;/code&gt; to open secret setting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-software4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; set your hostname and remember it we will be needing it later&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-software5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Click on Yes and let it complete it. After that, you will be granted this message so it means that it is been completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-software6.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;step-2&#34;&gt;Step 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that plug, it into pi and power it on, well as the pi is doing some process grab a cup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt; and wait for a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://gifimage.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/gif-a-few-moment-later.gif&#34; alt=&#34;A few moments later&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up your terminal and enter the following command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# as you remember I have told you to set your hostname in the software and remember it.
ssh pi@hostname.local
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replace your hostname with the hostname you have set while preparing the sd card. In my case, I have set my hostname with datacenter so my command will be like this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh pi@datacenter.local
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/terminal-pi-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pi Login&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as soon as you hit enter it will as you for a conformation like this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;~ ➤ ssh pi@datacenter.local                                                   
The authenticity of host &#39;datacenter.local (192.168.32.200)&#39; can&#39;t be established.
ECDSA key fingerprint is SHA256:VlnqrEfP5pLc62h2TQbN0Z4pEudRsmRQL4+LqDD6ZB8.
Are you sure you want to continue connecting (yes/no/[fingerprint])?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;answer it with &lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt; after that it will as you for a password which we have set during the software installation. As you have given the password right then you will see that you have been login into your account successfully like I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/pi-login.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pi Login Successful&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulation we have been login successfully into our pi take a break grab a cup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt; and relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-software-setup&#34;&gt;Step 2 Software setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we successfully login into pi first we will update the repository as well as we will be upgrading it by the following command don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you haven&amp;rsquo;t used Linux in your life this will be your first experience as well as it will be really easy just follow my steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;update-and-upgradation-of-packages&#34;&gt;Update and Upgradation of packages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt update
sudo apt upgrade -y
sudo apt full-upgrade -y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above command will update the repositories as well as it will be upgrading all the packages which are outdated so that we don&amp;rsquo;t get any kind of error while installing our NAS software. It will take a few minutes after all the process is completed we will check once again if there is any software that is left to upgrade by the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt list --upgradable
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following command will check whether any package is upgradable or not, if its all upgrade then it will return it with this message&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/pi-updated.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pi updated&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;packages-installation&#34;&gt;Packages installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we will be requirement few software for NAS to install without any error follow me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt install wget htop -y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;These packages are preinstalled but in some cases, these packages are not been installed so we will be making sure that it&amp;rsquo;s installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;script-installation&#34;&gt;Script installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script will not affect your network connection but if it did then I will leave a tutorial at the end of installation (&lt;a href=&#34;#wi-fi-setup&#34;&gt;Wi-Fi setup&lt;/a&gt;). Clear your terminal by using the &lt;code&gt;clear&lt;/code&gt; command it will clear your terminal so that you can see it easily. Now past this script into the terminal so that installation start&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget https://github.com/OpenMediaVault-Plugin-Developers/installScript/raw/master/install
chmod +x install
sudo ./install -n
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sit back and relax until the process is been done till that time go ahead and give me a cup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt; so that I can bring up various kinds of this topic so that you can enjoy it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/nas-installation-complete.png&#34; alt=&#34;Install complate&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Congratulation it&amp;rsquo;s been installed completed for our protection we will reboot our system with the following command &lt;code&gt;sudo reboot&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-nas-setup-on-browser&#34;&gt;Step 3 NAS setup on browser&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in &lt;a href=&#34;#step-2-software-setup&#34;&gt;Step 2 Software setup&lt;/a&gt; we have installed once again we will be login into ssh account to check the IP address of our Pi use the following command to check the IP address&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hostname -I
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/hostname.png&#34; alt=&#34;Finding IP address&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After finding your IP address use that IP address and open it in the browser with &lt;code&gt;https://your_ip_address&lt;/code&gt; and it will grant you this page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/openmediavault.png&#34; alt=&#34;OpenMediaVault&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now now don&amp;rsquo;t be frightened of the login page because you don&amp;rsquo;t know the password and username well of course I also don&amp;rsquo;t know. Just joking type the following and it will let you in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-txt&#34; data-lang=&#34;txt&#34;&gt;username: admin
password: openmediavault
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Congratulation you have successfully login, now before doing anything we will go ahead and change the password you will grant with this screen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-admin.png&#34; alt=&#34;Admin Panel&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;changing-admin-panel-password&#34;&gt;Changing admin panel password&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;strong&gt;System&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;raquo; &lt;strong&gt;General Settings&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;raquo; Click on &lt;strong&gt;Web Administrator Password&lt;/strong&gt; then enter your new password after doing that we will plug in any kind of hard drive or some sort of memory storing device&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-password-change.png&#34; alt=&#34;Password Change&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;storage-setup&#34;&gt;Storage setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have inserted external storage head over to &lt;strong&gt;Storage&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;raquo; &lt;strong&gt;Disk&lt;/strong&gt; and there you will be able to see your storage mounted on pi in my case I have inserted 128GB of memory card for the testing purpose also I have a few files copied into it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-disk.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notices error&#34; data-title=&#34;Warning&#34;&gt;
  We will be deleting all the data from the drive so make sure you do a backup of it.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the disk and then click on Wipe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-disk-wipe.png&#34; alt=&#34;Disk Wipe&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;![Disk Wipe]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have confirmed that our storage is been mounted on our pi now we will make a shared folder so that we can access it from any device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-storage-delete.png&#34; alt=&#34;Storage Delete&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now select the quick option&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-storage-delete-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Storage Delete&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;file-system-setup&#34;&gt;File System setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wiping the data from the drive click on &lt;code&gt;File System&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;Storage&lt;/code&gt; section. Click on Add button and select &lt;code&gt;Device&lt;/code&gt; and select the device and give it a label of your choice I will be giving it the name DataCenter, and make sure that you select &lt;code&gt;EXT4&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;File System&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-adding-device.png&#34; alt=&#34;Adding Device&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After hitting Yes to add device take a cup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt; and wait for it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-adding-device-complete.png&#34; alt=&#34;Adding Device Complete&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select your device and click on the mount option to mount your device. A pop-up has been visible on the top just hit on the &lt;code&gt;Apply&lt;/code&gt; button to apply changes so that to make sure that what are we going to make changes will work properly. It will take a few minutes to complete the process.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notices warning&#34; data-title=&#34;Notice&#34;&gt;
  whenever you see the &lt;code&gt;Apply&lt;/code&gt; button on the top right then click it and Apply the following changes.
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sharing-folder-setup&#34;&gt;Sharing Folder setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-folder-setup.png&#34; alt=&#34;Folder Sharing&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now we will head to &lt;code&gt;Sharing Folder Setup&lt;/code&gt; to set up our sharing folder. Go to &lt;code&gt;Access Rights Management&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Shared Folders&lt;/code&gt;  when you will go there you will find it empty because we haven&amp;rsquo;t set up any sharing folder go ahead and hit that &lt;code&gt;Add&lt;/code&gt; button without any thoughts.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-folder-setup-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Folder Sharing Setup&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill in all the details according to your need and make sure to leave &lt;code&gt;Permission&lt;/code&gt; as it is until and unless you know the purpose of it. I will be labeling it as DataCenter if you want to comment on that device then you can otherwise Save it, again you will see Apply button on the top right side of the screen as shown in the image below it will take a while to apply the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-folder-setup-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Folder Sharing Setup&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will permit it so that we can &lt;code&gt;Read/Write&lt;/code&gt; files into it. Select your newly created folder and click &lt;code&gt;Privileges&lt;/code&gt; and give &lt;code&gt;Read/Write&lt;/code&gt; to both pi users. Hit save and apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;services-setup&#34;&gt;Services Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to the &lt;strong&gt;Services&lt;/strong&gt; section and select &lt;code&gt;SMB/CIFS&lt;/code&gt; as soon as you select it you will be granted a screen with soo many scary options but don&amp;rsquo;t worry we will be using only 2 options only. So go ahead and click sharing in the &lt;code&gt;SMB/CIFS&lt;/code&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-service-smb-page.png&#34; alt=&#34;Samba Service&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-services-smb-share.png&#34; alt=&#34;Samba Service&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go ahead click on the &lt;code&gt;Add&lt;/code&gt; button select your shared folder which you have been created. Hit save and apply don&amp;rsquo;t change any other kind of options if your expert then only does it or else let it be as it is. Go back to the &lt;code&gt;SMB/CIFS&lt;/code&gt; setting page and enable it. Hit save and apply. Take a cup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;coffee&lt;/a&gt; and relax for a bit because we are coming to the most intrusting part which is accessing it from our devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;accessing-our-nas&#34;&gt;Accessing our NAS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gwM9RaemCvE&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Before we move on &lt;code&gt;Windows User&lt;/code&gt; please see the above video to enable &lt;code&gt;SMB&lt;/code&gt;, as I&amp;rsquo;m on Ubuntu I can directly access it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-nas-folder.png&#34; alt=&#34;NAS Test&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-nas-auth.png&#34; alt=&#34;NAS Test&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you try to access it, it will as you for authentication so use your pi account and password which you used while setting up os if it fails then go to &lt;code&gt;Access Rights Management&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt;, select pi user, and edit it after that add your new password and save it. go back to the folder and try to login back and you will be successfully logged in to NAS Folder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/omv-nas-folder-access.png&#34; alt=&#34;NAS Folder Access&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wi-fi-setup&#34;&gt;Wi-Fi Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re going to use Wi-Fi then connect to a monitor and attach a keyboard then simply type the following command in the terminal to access the raspberry pi configuration setup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo raspi-config
# it will represent you with the screen bellow
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-wifi-setup.png&#34; alt=&#34;Wifi Setup&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;System Options&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Wireless LAN&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; Enter your Wi-Fi Name &amp;gt; Enter your Wi-Fi password&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-wifi-setup-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Wifi Setup&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-wifi-setup-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Wifi Setup&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/raspberrypi-wifi-setup-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Wifi Setup&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing all the above steps reboot your system with &lt;code&gt;sudo reboot&lt;/code&gt; and bam done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mr-blogger&#34;&gt;Mr. Blogger&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/show/6p14uYsO8NtWD8tM3wEd4o&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;232&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;social-media&#34;&gt;Social Media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram - &lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;https://instagram.com/mistrysiddh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github - &lt;a href=&#34;https://guthub.com/mrfoxie&#34;&gt;https://guthub.com/mrfoxie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linkedin - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/SiddhMistry/&#34;&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/SiddhMistry/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whatsapp - &lt;a href=&#34;https://api.whatsapp.com/send?phone=916355040470&amp;amp;text=http%3A%2F%2Fmistrysiddh.tk%2F&#34;&gt;Message Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord - &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/bPrBSbQ2W4&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/bPrBSbQ2W4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;donation&#34;&gt;Donation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paypal - &lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;https://paypal.me/mistrysiddh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patreon - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/siddhmistry&#34;&gt;https://www.patreon.com/siddhmistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buymeacoffee - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mistrysiddh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;play-store&#34;&gt;Play Store&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/2Vch9gi&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://play.google.com/intl/en_us/badges/static/images/badges/en_badge_web_generic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get it on Google Play&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="/https://i.ytimg.com/vi/Jc4Y2jA4Yeg/maxresdefault.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>new site</category>
            
          
            
              <category>technology</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Linux</category>
            
          
            
              <category>industrial automation</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Industrial automation</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Hacking</category>
            
          
            
              <category>website</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Hacking</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating a Website on Raspberry Pi at home</title>
        <link>/create-own-website-at-home/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 22:24:13 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 22:27:42 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>/create-own-website-at-home/</guid>
        <description>Overview This is perfect for setting up your first website and learning not only administering a wordpress site, but learning Linux. You will need a Raspberry Pi, a couple hours, and a computer to download the image on. The Raspberry Pi (RPI) is a perfect device for learning these things.
Also check out the official projects site from RaspberryPi
Source: https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/lamp-web-server-with-wordpress
Downloading the RPI Imager Download the Imager for your operating system.</description>
        <content:encoded>



  



  &lt;div class=&#34;featured-image__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/QdHvS0D1zAI/maxresdefault.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Featured Image&#34; class=&#34;featured-image&#34; style=&#34;width: ;height: ;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is perfect for setting up your first website and learning not only administering a wordpress site, but learning Linux. You will need a Raspberry Pi, a couple hours, and a computer to download the image on. The Raspberry Pi (RPI) is a perfect device for learning these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also check out the official projects site from RaspberryPi&lt;br /&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/lamp-web-server-with-wordpress&#34;&gt;https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/lamp-web-server-with-wordpress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;downloading-the-rpi-imager&#34;&gt;Downloading the RPI Imager&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the Imager for your operating system. This supports all three OS’s (Windows, Mac, and Linux).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;https://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run and Install the Imager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select Raspberry Pi OS (other) -&amp;gt; Raspberry Pi OS Lite (32-bit)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: This is the one with NO Desktop Environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insert the SD Card into your Computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Write&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-dependencies&#34;&gt;Install Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install apache2 php mariadb-server php-mysql -y
sudo service apache2 restart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-wordpress&#34;&gt;Install Wordpress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd /var/www/html/
sudo rm *
sudo wget http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gz
sudo tar xzf latest.tar.gz
sudo mv wordpress/* .
sudo rm -rf wordpress latest.tar.gz
sudo chown -R www-data: .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup-wordpress-database&#34;&gt;Setup WordPress Database&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mysql_secure_installation
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will be asked Enter current password for root (enter for none): — press Enter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type in Y and press Enter to Set root password?.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type in a password at the New password: prompt, and press Enter. Important: remember this root password, as you will need it later to set up WordPress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type in Y to Remove anonymous users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type in Y to Disallow root login remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type in Y to Remove test database and access to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type in Y to Reload privilege tables now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When complete, you will see the message All done! and Thanks for using MariaDB!.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Login to MySQL with &lt;code&gt;sudo mysql -uroot -p&lt;/code&gt; and enter the password you set above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will see the terminal prompt change and you can enter the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;create database wordpress;
GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON wordpress.* TO &#39;root&#39;@&#39;localhost&#39; IDENTIFIED BY &#39;YOURPASSWORD&#39;;
FLUSH PRIVILEGES;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IMPORTANT: Exit SQL Prompt with &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + D&lt;/code&gt; and change &lt;code&gt;YOURPASSWORD&lt;/code&gt; above to your password!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reboot with &lt;code&gt;sudo reboot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wordpress-configuration&#34;&gt;Wordpress Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote Access can be done with SSH from any system. Find your Raspberry Pi IP with &lt;code&gt;ip a&lt;/code&gt;. This IP is only your Local IP and not accessible from the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial setup can be done from any computer in the same network as the RPI. Type your pi ip address from above into your browsers address bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example: &lt;a href=&#34;https://127.0.0.1&#34;&gt;https://127.0.0.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote Login after initial setup append &lt;code&gt;/wp-admin&lt;/code&gt; to the address&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example: &lt;a href=&#34;https://127.0.0.1/wp-adin&#34;&gt;https://127.0.0.1/wp-admin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommended-server-settings&#34;&gt;Recommended Server settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we need to make some quality of life improvements so you don’t have weird looking addresses. This is called “Friendly Permalinks”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;WP Admin Portal&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;em&gt;Setting&lt;/em&gt;, then &lt;em&gt;Permalinks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the &lt;em&gt;Post name&lt;/em&gt; option and click &lt;em&gt;Save Changes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;em&gt;SSH or Terminal on the RPI&lt;/em&gt; you need to enter the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo a2enmod rewrite
sudo nano /etc/apache2/sites-available/000-default.conf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;000-default.conf edits (Add this midway in the file)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Directory &amp;quot;/var/www/html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    AllowOverride All
&amp;lt;/Directory&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save the File by press Ctrl + O and Exit with Ctrl + X&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now restart Apache Web with &lt;code&gt;sudo service apache2 restart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mr-blogger&#34;&gt;Mr. Blogger&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/show/6p14uYsO8NtWD8tM3wEd4o&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;232&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;encrypted-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;social-media&#34;&gt;Social Media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram - &lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;https://instagram.com/mistrysiddh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github - &lt;a href=&#34;https://guthub.com/mrfoxie&#34;&gt;https://guthub.com/mrfoxie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linkedin - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/SiddhMistry/&#34;&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/SiddhMistry/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whatsapp - &lt;a href=&#34;https://api.whatsapp.com/send?phone=916355040470&amp;amp;text=http%3A%2F%2Fmistrysiddh.tk%2F&#34;&gt;Message Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord - &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/bPrBSbQ2W4&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/bPrBSbQ2W4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;donation&#34;&gt;Donation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paypal - &lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;https://paypal.me/mistrysiddh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patreon - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/siddhmistry&#34;&gt;https://www.patreon.com/siddhmistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buymeacoffee - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mistrysiddh&#34;&gt;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/mistrysiddh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;play-store&#34;&gt;Play Store&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/2Vch9gi&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://play.google.com/intl/en_us/badges/static/images/badges/en_badge_web_generic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get it on Google Play&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="/https://i.ytimg.com/vi/QdHvS0D1zAI/maxresdefault.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>new site</category>
            
          
            
              <category>technology</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Linux</category>
            
          
            
              <category>industrial automation</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Industrial automation</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Hacking</category>
            
          
            
              <category>website</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Hacking</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>WSL Graphics</title>
        <link>/run-linux-gui-apps-on-wsl2/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 09:59:27 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 22:27:42 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>/run-linux-gui-apps-on-wsl2/</guid>
        <description>Recaps In previous post we have seen how to install Windows Subsystem Linux in your windows 10, so in this we will see how to use GUI on your system without any kind of software or other utilities. The main purpose of using this is so that you can easily use both the windows and Linux apps together on single operating system, after you have installed this WSLG on your system it will look like this.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&#34;recaps&#34;&gt;Recaps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In previous post we have seen how to install &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/wsl2install&#34;&gt;Windows Subsystem Linux&lt;/a&gt; in your windows 10, so in this we will see how to use &lt;strong&gt;GUI&lt;/strong&gt; on your system without any kind of software or other utilities. The main purpose of using this is so that you can easily use both the windows and Linux apps together on single operating system, after you have installed this WSLG on your system it will look like this.&lt;/p&gt;




  



  &lt;div class=&#34;featured-image__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/WSLg_IntegratedDesktop.png&#34; alt=&#34;Featured Image&#34; class=&#34;featured-image&#34; style=&#34;width: ;height: ;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start the installation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brief-introduction&#34;&gt;Brief Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WSLg is short for &lt;em&gt;Windows Subsystem for Linux GUI&lt;/em&gt; and the purpose of the project is to enable support for running Linux GUI applications (X11 and Wayland) on Windows in a fully integrated desktop experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WSLg provides an integrated experience for developers, scientists or enthusiasts that prefer or need to run Windows on their PC but also need the ability to run tools or applications which works best, or exclusively, in a Linux environment. While users can accomplish this today using a multiple system setup, with individual PC dedicated to Windows and Linux, virtual machine hosting either Windows or Linux, or an XServer running on Windows and projected into WSL, WSLg provides a more integrated, user friendly and productive alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WSLg strives to make Linux GUI applications feel native and natural to use on Windows. From integration into the Start Menu for launch to appearing in the task bar, alt-tab experience to enabling cut/paste across Windows and Linux applications, WSLg enables a seamless desktop experience and workflow leveraging Windows and Linux applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pre-requirements&#34;&gt;Pre-requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you begin installation of WSLG you have to check few thing on your system so that there is no error while installation. Here are the requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; &lt;code&gt;Windows 10 Insider Preview build 21362+&lt;/code&gt; (required for now but in future it will be available for normal builds if you aren&amp;rsquo;t on this build then go to setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/wsl2install/#installation-of-wsl-2&#34;&gt;Windows Insider&lt;/a&gt; and get latest versions of Insider Preview build)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Choose your GPU (if you have already install drivers then you can skip this steps)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.amd.com/community/radeon-pro-graphics/blog/2020/06/17/announcing-amd-support-for-gpu-accelerated-machine-learning-training-on-windows-10&#34;&gt;AMD GPU driver for WSL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://downloadcenter.intel.com/download/29526&#34;&gt;Intel GPU driver for WSL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.nvidia.com/cuda/wsl&#34;&gt;NVIDIA GPU driver for WSL&lt;/a&gt; (I have NVIDIA GeForce on my device so I have already installed it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-instructions&#34;&gt;Install instructions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assume that you have installed WSL on your system but if you haven&amp;rsquo;t installed it yet then go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/ws2install/&#34;&gt;WSL2 Installation&lt;/a&gt; and install it. Moving further If you have an existing WSL installation without WSLg and want to update to the latest version of WSL which includes WSLg, run the command &lt;code&gt;wsl --update&lt;/code&gt; from an elevated command prompt, and also download and install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/wslg/releases/tag/v1.0.24&#34;&gt;Linux GUI support&lt;/a&gt; on your system so that the software requirement to run WSLg will be installed automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34; data-dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Please note that WSLg is only compatible with WSL 2 and will not work for WSL distribution configured to work in WSL 1 mode. Verify that your Linux distro is configured for running in WSL 2 mode, if not switch to WSL 2. While you can continue to run Linux distro in WSL 1 mode after installing WSLg if you so desired, a distro configured to run in WSL 1 mode will not be able to communicate with WSLg and will not be able to run GUI applications.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can list your currently installed distro and the version of WSL they are configured for using the following command from an elevated command prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;   &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;wsl&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;-list&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;-v&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If running in version 1 mode, switch to version 2. This can take a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;   &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;wsl&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;-set-version&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;_distro_name_&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Restart WSL by running this command from an elevated command prompt, make sure to save any pending work first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;wsl&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;-shutdown&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating-wsl--wslg&#34;&gt;Updating WSL + WSLg&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To update to the latest version of WSL and WSLg released for preview, simply run &lt;code&gt;wsl --update&lt;/code&gt; from an elevated command prompt or powershell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need to restart WSL for the changes to take effect. You can restart WSL by running &lt;code&gt;wsl --shutdown&lt;/code&gt; from an elevated command prompt. If WSL was currently running, it will shutdown, make sure to first save any in progress work! WSL will be automatically restarted the next time you launch a WSL application or terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-launch&#34;&gt;First Launch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have installed the &lt;code&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/code&gt; Linux distro per these instructions, you&amp;rsquo;ll find an &lt;code&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/code&gt; icon in your start menu, launch it. This will launch the WSL 2 VM, launch the Ubuntu WSL distro in that VM and give you a terminal to interact with it. Voila! You&amp;rsquo;re running Linux on Windows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to explore additional Linux distributions built for WSL, you can use the &lt;code&gt;wsl --list --online&lt;/code&gt; command from an elevated command prompt to enumerate the list of available distributions for your system. You can have multiple Linux distributions installed within WSL and they will happily coexist side-by-side, so don&amp;rsquo;t be scared to experiment and try things out. Now let&amp;rsquo;s install and try some apps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-and-run-gui-apps&#34;&gt;Install and run GUI apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get started with some GUI apps, you can run the following commands from your Linux terminal to download and install some popular applications. If you are using a different distribution than Ubuntu, it may be using a different package manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Update all packages in your distro
sudo apt update

## Gedit
sudo apt install gedit -y

## GIMP
sudo apt install gimp -y

## Nautilus
sudo apt install nautilus -y

## VLC
sudo apt install vlc -y

## X11 apps
sudo apt install x11-apps -y

## Google Chrome
cd /tmp
sudo wget https://dl.google.com/linux/direct/google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb
sudo dpkg -i google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb 
sudo apt install --fix-broken -y
sudo dpkg -i google-chrome-stable_current_amd64.deb

## Microsoft Teams
cd /tmp
sudo curl -L -o &amp;quot;./teams.deb&amp;quot; &amp;quot;https://teams.microsoft.com/downloads/desktopurl?env=production&amp;amp;plat=linux&amp;amp;arch=x64&amp;amp;download=true&amp;amp;linuxArchiveType=deb&amp;quot;
sudo apt install ./teams.deb -y

## Microsoft Edge Browser
sudo curl https://packages.microsoft.com/repos/edge/pool/main/m/microsoft-edge-dev/microsoft-edge-dev_91.0.852.0-1_amd64.deb -o /tmp/edge.deb
sudo apt install /tmp/edge.deb -y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once these applications are installed, you&amp;rsquo;ll find them in your start menu under the distro name. For example &lt;code&gt;Ubuntu -&amp;gt; Microsoft Edge&lt;/code&gt;. You can also launch these from your terminal window using the commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xcalc&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;xclock&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;xeyes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gimp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gedit ~/.bashrc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;nautilus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;vlc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;google-chrome&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;teams&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;microsoft-edge&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congrats you are done and ready to use GUI apps!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="/images/posts/WSLg_IntegratedDesktop.png" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>technology</category>
            
          
            
              <category>wsl</category>
            
          
            
              <category>wsl2</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Linux</category>
            
          
            
              <category>ubuntu</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>technology</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Hacking</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Windows</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>WSL Install</title>
        <link>/install-linux-on-windows/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 12:01:11 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 22:27:42 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>/install-linux-on-windows/</guid>
        <description>What is WSL? The Windows Subsystem for Linux lets developers(WSL) run a GNU/Linux environment &amp;ndash; including most command-line tools, utilities, and applications &amp;ndash; directly on Windows, unmodified, without the overhead of a traditional virtual machine or dual-boot setup.
You can:
 Choose your favorite GNU/Linux distributions from the Microsoft Store. Run common command-line tools such as grep, sed, awk, or other ELF-64 binaries. Run Bash shell scripts and GNU/Linux command-line applications including:  Tools: vim, emacs, tmux Languages: NodeJS, Javascript, Python, Ruby, C/C++, C## &amp;amp; F##, Rust, Go, etc.</description>
        <content:encoded>



  



  &lt;div class=&#34;featured-image__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;/images/posts/wsl2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Featured Image&#34; class=&#34;featured-image&#34; style=&#34;width: ;height: ;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-wsl&#34;&gt;What is WSL?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Windows Subsystem for Linux lets developers(WSL) run a GNU/Linux environment &amp;ndash; including most command-line tools, utilities, and applications &amp;ndash; directly on Windows, unmodified, without the overhead of a traditional virtual machine or dual-boot setup.&lt;br /&gt;
You can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose your favorite GNU/Linux distributions from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/wslstore&#34;&gt;Microsoft Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run common command-line tools such as grep, sed, awk, or other ELF-64 binaries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Bash shell scripts and GNU/Linux command-line applications including:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools: vim, emacs, tmux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Languages: NodeJS, Javascript, Python, Ruby, C/C++, C## &amp;amp; F##, Rust, Go, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Services: SSHD, MySQL, Apache, Lighttpd, MongoDB, PostgreSQL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install additional software using your own GNU/Linux distribution package manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invoke Windows applications using a Unix-like command-line shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invoke GNU/Linux applications on Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-wsl-2&#34;&gt;What is WSL 2?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WSL 2 is a new version of the Windows Subsystem for Linux architecture that powers the Windows Subsystem for Linux to run ELF64 Linux binaries on Windows. Its primary goals are to increase file system performance, as well as adding full system call compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new architecture changes how these Linux binaries interact with Windows and your computer&amp;rsquo;s hardware, but still provides the same user experience as in WSL 1 (the current widely available version).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual Linux distributions can be run with either the WSL 1 or WSL 2 architecture. Each distribution can be upgraded or downgraded at any time and you can run WSL 1 and WSL 2 distributions side by side. WSL 2 uses an entirely new architecture that benefits from running a real Linux kernel. Let&amp;rsquo;s see the comparison between &lt;code&gt;WSL 1&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;WSL 2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparing-wsl-1-and-wsl-2&#34;&gt;Comparing WSL 1 and WSL 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary difference and reasons for updating the Windows Subsystem for Linux from WSL 1 to WSL 2 are to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;increase file system performance,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support full system call compatibility.&lt;br /&gt;
WSL 2 uses the latest and greatest in virtualization technology to run a Linux kernel inside of a lightweight utility virtual machine (VM). However, WSL 2 is not a traditional VM experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comparing-features&#34;&gt;Comparing features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;WSL 1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;WSL 2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Integration between Windows and Linux&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fast boot times&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Small resource foot print compared to traditional Virtual Machines&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Runs with current versions of VMware and VirtualBox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Managed VM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Full Linux Kernel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Full system call compatibility&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Performance across OS file systems&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance-across-os-file-systems&#34;&gt;Performance across OS file systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend against working across operating systems with your files, unless you have a specific reason for doing so. For the fastest performance speed, store your files in the WSL file system if you are working in a Linux command line (Ubuntu, OpenSUSE, etc). If you&amp;rsquo;re working in a Windows command line (PowerShell, Command Prompt), store your files in the Windows file system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, when storing your WSL project files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the Linux file system root directory: &lt;code&gt;\\wsl$\Ubuntu-18.04\home\&amp;lt;user name&amp;gt;\Project&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not the Windows file system root directory: &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\&amp;lt;user name&amp;gt;\Project&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All currently running distributions (&lt;code&gt;wsl -l&lt;/code&gt;) are accessible via network connection. To get there run a command [WIN+R] (keyboard shortcut) or type in File Explorer address bar &lt;code&gt;\\wsl$&lt;/code&gt; to find respective distribution names and access their root file systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use windows commands inside WSL&amp;rsquo;s Linux &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_console&#34;&gt;Terminal&lt;/a&gt;. Try opening a Linux distribution (ie Ubuntu), be sure that you are in the Linux home directory by entering this command: &lt;code&gt;cd ~&lt;/code&gt;. Then open your Linux file system in File Explorer by entering &lt;em&gt;(don&amp;rsquo;t forget the period at the end)&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;code&gt;powershell.exe /c start .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WSL 2 is only available in Windows 10, Version 1903, Build 18362 or higher. Check your Windows version by selecting the &lt;strong&gt;Windows logo key + R&lt;/strong&gt;, type &lt;strong&gt;winver&lt;/strong&gt;, select &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;. (Or enter the &lt;code&gt;ver&lt;/code&gt; command in Windows Command Prompt). You may need to &lt;a href=&#34;ms-settings:windowsupdate&#34;&gt;update to the latest Windows version&lt;/a&gt;. For builds lower than 18362, WSL is not supported at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation-of-wsl-2&#34;&gt;Installation of WSL 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two options available for installing Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10#simplified-installation-for-windows-insiders&#34;&gt;Simplified install&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(preview release)&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;code&gt;wsl --install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;wsl --install&lt;/code&gt; simplified install command requires that you join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://insider.windows.com/getting-started&#34;&gt;Windows Insiders Program&lt;/a&gt; and install a preview build of Windows 10 (OS build 20262 or higher), but eliminates the need to follow the manual install steps. All you need to do is open a command window with administrator privileges and run &lt;code&gt;wsl --install&lt;/code&gt;, after a restart you will be ready to use WSL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;manual-installation-steps&#34;&gt;Manual Installation Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not on a Windows Insiders build, the features required for WSL will need to be enabled manually following the steps below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-1---enable-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux&#34;&gt;Step 1 - Enable the Windows Subsystem for Linux&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must first enable the &amp;ldquo;Windows Subsystem for Linux&amp;rdquo; optional feature before installing any Linux distributions on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open PowerShell as Administrator and run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;dism&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;online&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;enable-feature&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;featurename&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Microsoft-Windows-Subsystem-Linux&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;norestart&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-2---check-requirements-for-running-wsl-2&#34;&gt;Step 2 - Check requirements for running WSL 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To update to WSL 2, you must be running Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For x64 systems: &lt;strong&gt;Version 1903&lt;/strong&gt; or higher, with &lt;strong&gt;Build 18362&lt;/strong&gt; or higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For ARM64 systems: &lt;strong&gt;Version 2004&lt;/strong&gt; or higher, with &lt;strong&gt;Build 19041&lt;/strong&gt; or higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Builds lower than 18362 do not support WSL 2. Use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/software-download/windows10&#34;&gt;Windows Update Assistant&lt;/a&gt; to update your version of Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-danger&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34; data-dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;If you are running Windows 10 version 1903 or 1909, open &amp;ldquo;Settings&amp;rdquo; from your Windows menu, navigate to &amp;ldquo;Update &amp;amp; Security&amp;rdquo; and select &amp;ldquo;Check for Updates&amp;rdquo;. Your Build number must be 18362.1049+ or 18363.1049+, with the minor build # over .1049. Read more: &lt;a href=&#34;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/wsl-2-support-is-coming-to-windows-10-versions-1903-and-1909/&#34;&gt;WSL 2 Support is coming to Windows 10 Versions 1903 and 1909&lt;/a&gt;. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/troubleshooting#im-on-windows-10-version-1903-and-i-still-do-not-see-options-for-wsl-2&#34;&gt;troubleshooting instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3---enable-virtual-machine-feature&#34;&gt;Step 3 - Enable Virtual Machine feature&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before installing WSL 2, you must enable the &lt;strong&gt;Virtual Machine Platform&lt;/strong&gt; optional feature. Your machine will require &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/troubleshooting#error-0x80370102-the-virtual-machine-could-not-be-started-because-a-required-feature-is-not-installed&#34;&gt;virtualization capabilities&lt;/a&gt; to use this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open PowerShell as Administrator and run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;dism&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;online&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;enable-feature&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;featurename&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;VirtualMachinePlatform&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;norestart&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restart&lt;/strong&gt; your machine to complete the WSL install and update to WSL 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-4---download-the-linux-kernel-update-package&#34;&gt;Step 4 - Download the Linux kernel update package&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the latest package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wslstorestorage.blob.core.windows.net/wslblob/wsl_update_x64.msi&#34;&gt;WSL2 Linux kernel update package for x64 machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-danger&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34; data-dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using an ARM64 machine, please download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wslstorestorage.blob.core.windows.net/wslblob/wsl_update_arm64.msi&#34;&gt;ARM64 package&lt;/a&gt; instead. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what kind of machine you have, open Command Prompt or PowerShell and enter: &lt;code&gt;systeminfo | find &amp;quot;System Type&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Caveat:&lt;/strong&gt; On non-English Windows versions, you might have to modify the search text, for example, in German it would be &lt;code&gt;systeminfo | find &amp;quot;Systemtyp&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the update package downloaded in the previous step. (Double-click to run - you will be prompted for elevated permissions, select ‘yes’ to approve this installation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-5---set-wsl-2-as-your-default-version&#34;&gt;Step 5 - Set WSL 2 as your default version&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open PowerShell and run this command to set WSL 2 as the default version when installing a new Linux distribution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;wsl&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;-set-default-version&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-6---install-your-linux-distribution-of-choice&#34;&gt;Step 6 - Install your Linux distribution of choice&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manual installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are on &lt;code&gt;Windows 10 Insider Preview build 21362+&lt;/code&gt; then just type the following commands in powershell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c&#34;&gt;#this command will show you list of all distribution which is been supported by windows&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;wsl&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;-list&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;-online&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;as soon as paste the above command you will get this message there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;PS C:\Users\SIDDH&amp;gt; wsl --list --online
The following is a list of valid distributions that can be installed.
Install using &#39;wsl --install -d &amp;lt;Distro&amp;gt;&#39;.

NAME            FRIENDLY NAME
Ubuntu          Ubuntu
Debian          Debian GNU/Linux
kali-linux      Kali Linux Rolling
openSUSE-42     openSUSE Leap 42
SLES-12         SUSE Linux Enterprise Server v12
Ubuntu-16.04    Ubuntu 16.04 LTS
Ubuntu-18.04    Ubuntu 18.04 LTS
Ubuntu-20.04    Ubuntu 20.04 LTS
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;you can choose any of the distro you want to install in your system say for example if you want to install Ubuntu then just past the following command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;wsl&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;-install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;-d&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;ubuntu&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;and it will start installing into your system after completion it will ask you for a username and password set those two parameters and you will be able to use Ubuntu in your system without dual-boot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/media/ubuntuinstall.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ubuntu Install&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/wslstore&#34;&gt;Microsoft Store&lt;/a&gt; and select your favorite Linux distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/media/store.png&#34; alt=&#34;Microsoft Store&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following links will open the Microsoft store page for each distribution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9N9TNGVNDL3Q&#34;&gt;Ubuntu 18.04 LTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9n6svws3rx71&#34;&gt;Ubuntu 20.04 LTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9NJFZK00FGKV&#34;&gt;openSUSE Leap 15.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9MZ3D1TRP8T1&#34;&gt;SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 12 SP5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9PN498VPMF3Z&#34;&gt;SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 15 SP1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9PKR34TNCV07&#34;&gt;Kali Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9MSVKQC78PK6&#34;&gt;Debian GNU/Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9n6gdm4k2hnc&#34;&gt;Fedora Remix for WSL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9NV1GV1PXZ6P&#34;&gt;Pengwin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9N8LP0X93VCP&#34;&gt;Pengwin Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9p804crf0395&#34;&gt;Alpine WSL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;install-windows-terminal-optional&#34;&gt;Install Windows Terminal (optional)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows Terminal enables multiple tabs (quickly switch between multiple Linux command lines, Windows Command Prompt, PowerShell, Azure CLI, etc), create custom key bindings (shortcut keys for opening or closing tabs, copy+paste, etc.), use the search feature, and custom themes (color schemes, font styles and sizes, background image/blur/transparency).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/terminal/get-started&#34;&gt;Install Windows Terminal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/media/terminal.png&#34; alt=&#34;Windows Terminal&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can use linux as well as windows at a same time. In next post we will be seeing how to GUI app in WSL2.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="/images/posts/wsl2.png" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>technology</category>
            
          
            
              <category>wsl</category>
            
          
            
              <category>wsl2</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Linux</category>
            
          
            
              <category>ubuntu</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>technology</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Hacking</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Windows</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      

    
  </channel>
</rss>