<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" 
  xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>robotics on Mr. Blogger</title>
    <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/categories/robotics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in robotics on Mr. Blogger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><hosted>Netlify -- netlify.com</hosted>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 20:43:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    
        <atom:link href="https://mistrysiddh.tk/categories/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    

      
      <item>
        <title>Nanotechnology</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/nanotechnology/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 20:43:49 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Thu, 06 May 2021 23:34:30 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/nanotechnology/</guid>
        <description>What is Nanotechnology? Nanotechnology is science, engineering, and technology conducted at the nanoscale, which is about 1 to 100 nanometers. Nanoscience and nanotechnology are the study and application of extremely small things and can be used across all the other science fields, such as chemistry, biology, physics, materials science, and engineering. It is the leading technology in the world where all the material are been made on the nanoscale level, you must have not been noticed that Microcontroller which we are using in our circuits and much more applications are been made up to the nanoscale level which is called VLSI Very Large Scale Integration.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-nanotechnology&#34;&gt;What is Nanotechnology?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;



  



  &lt;div class=&#34;featured-image__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/nanotechnology.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Featured Image&#34; class=&#34;featured-image&#34; style=&#34;width: ;height: ;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Nanotechnology is science, engineering, and technology conducted at the nanoscale, which is about 1 to 100 nanometers. Nanoscience and nanotechnology are the study and application of extremely small things and can be used across all the other science fields, such as chemistry, biology, physics, materials science, and engineering. It is the leading technology in the world where all the material are been made on the nanoscale level, you must have not been noticed that &lt;code&gt;Microcontroller&lt;/code&gt; which we are using in our circuits and much more applications are been made up to the nanoscale level which is called &lt;code&gt;VLSI&lt;/code&gt; Very Large Scale Integration. Nanotechnology is also called nanotech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Wikipidia&lt;/sup&gt; The concepts that seeded nanotechnology were first discussed in 1959 by renowned physicist &lt;code&gt;Richard Feynman&lt;/code&gt; in his talk &lt;code&gt;There&#39;s Plenty of Room at the Bottom&lt;/code&gt;, in which he described the possibility of synthesis via direct manipulation of atoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;code&gt;Nanotechnology&lt;/code&gt; was first used by &lt;code&gt;Norio Taniguchi&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;1974&lt;/code&gt;, though it was not widely known. Inspired by Feynman&amp;rsquo;s concepts, &lt;code&gt;K. Eric Drexler&lt;/code&gt; used the term &lt;code&gt;nanotechnology&lt;/code&gt; in his 1986 book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pdfdrive.com/engines-of-creation-20-the-coming-era-of-nanotechnology-e158355030.html&#34;&gt;Engines of Creation: The Comming Era of Nanotechnology&lt;/a&gt; which proposed the idea of a nanoscale &amp;ldquo;assembler&amp;rdquo; which would be able to build a copy of itself and the items of arbitrary complexity with atomic control. It&amp;rsquo;s also been said that nanotechnology will be able to perform AI level operation which will help to eradicate those diseases which humans can&amp;rsquo;t remove it, say for example &lt;code&gt;AIDS&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Radioactive materials&lt;/code&gt; from the body, also this &lt;code&gt;CoronaVirus&lt;/code&gt; from current pandemic year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fundamental-concepts&#34;&gt;Fundamental Concepts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nanotechnology is the engineering of functional systems at the molecular scale. This covers both current work and concepts that are more advanced. In its original sense, nanotechnology refers to the projected ability to construct items from the bottom up, using techniques and tools being developed today to make complete, high performance products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One nanometer (nm) is one billionth, or 10−9, of a meter. By comparison, typical carbon-carbon bond lengths, or the spacing between these atoms in a molecule, are in the range 0.12–0.15 nm, and a DNA double-helix has a diameter around 2 nm. On the other hand, the smallest cellular life-forms, the bacteria of the genus Mycoplasma, are around 200 nm in length. By convention, nanotechnology is taken as the scale range 1 to 100 nm following the definition used by the National Nanotechnology Initiative in the US. The lower limit is set by the size of atoms (hydrogen has the smallest atoms, which are approximately a quarter of a nm kinetic diameter) since nanotechnology must build its devices from atoms and molecules. The upper limit is more or less arbitrary but is around the size below which phenomena not observed in larger structures start to become apparent and can be made use of in the nano device.[26] These new phenomena make nanotechnology distinct from devices which are merely miniaturised versions of an equivalent macroscopic device; such devices are on a larger scale and come under the description of microtechnology.[27]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put that scale in another context, the comparative size of a nanometer to a meter is the same as that of a marble to the size of the earth.[28] Or another way of putting it: a nanometer is the amount an average man&amp;rsquo;s beard grows in the time it takes him to raise the razor to his face.[28]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two main approaches are used in nanotechnology. In the &amp;ldquo;bottom-up&amp;rdquo; approach, materials and devices are built from molecular components which assemble themselves chemically by principles of molecular recognition.[29] In the &amp;ldquo;top-down&amp;rdquo; approach, nano-objects are constructed from larger entities without atomic-level control.[30]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Areas of physics such as nanoelectronics, nanomechanics, nanophotonics and nanoionics have evolved during the last few decades to provide a basic scientific foundation of nanotechnology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-research&#34;&gt;Current research&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nanomaterials&#34;&gt;Nanomaterials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nanomaterials field includes subfields which develop or study materials having unique properties arising from their nanoscale dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interface and colloid science has given rise to many materials which may be useful in nanotechnology, such as carbon nanotubes and other fullerenes, and various nanoparticles and nanorods. Nanomaterials with fast ion transport are related also to nanoionics and nanoelectronics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nanoscale materials can also be used for bulk applications; most present commercial applications of nanotechnology are of this flavor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progress has been made in using these materials for medical applications; see Nanomedicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nanoscale materials such as nanopillars are sometimes used in solar cells which combats the cost of traditional silicon solar cells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of applications incorporating semiconductor nanoparticles to be used in the next generation of products, such as display technology, lighting, solar cells and biological imaging; see quantum dots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent application of nanomaterials include a range of biomedical applications, such as tissue engineering, drug delivery, antibacterials and biosensors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-and-development&#34;&gt;Research and development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the variety of potential applications (including industrial and military), governments have invested billions of dollars in nanotechnology research. Prior to 2012, the USA invested $3.7 billion using its National Nanotechnology Initiative, the European Union invested $1.2 billion, and Japan invested $750 million. Over sixty countries created nanotechnology research and development (R&amp;amp;D) programs between 2001 and 2004. In 2012, the US and EU each invested $2.1 billion on nanotechnology research, followed by Japan with $1.2 billion. Global investment reached $7.9 billion in 2012. Government funding was exceeded by corporate R&amp;amp;D spending on nanotechnology research, which was $10 billion in 2012. The largest corporate R&amp;amp;D spenders were from the US, Japan and Germany which accounted for a combined $7.1 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Rank&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Organization&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Country&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;First Patents&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Samsung Electronics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;South Korea&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2578&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nippon Steel &amp;amp; Sumitomo Metal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1490&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IBM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1360&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Toshiba&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1298&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Canon Inc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1162&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hitachi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;University of California, Berkeley&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1055&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Panasonic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1047&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hewlett-Packard&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;United States&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;880&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TDK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Japan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;839&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/nanotechnology.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>technology</category>
            
          
            
              <category>robotics</category>
            
          
            
              <category>industrial automation</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>robotics</category>
            
          
            
              <category>technology</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Industrial automation</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Industrial 4.0</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Robotics</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/robotics/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 15:02:14 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Thu, 06 May 2021 23:34:30 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/robotics/</guid>
        <description>Robotics Robotics is the intersection of science, engineering and technology that produces machines, called robots, that substitute for (or replicate) human actions. As you have seen in the movie such as I robot, wall-e, Transformer etc. where robots are been there. As time passes technology also evolves not also that it gets smatter and smatter also.
What is a Robot? A robot is the product of the robotics field, where programmable machines are built that can assist humans or mimic human actions.</description>
        <content:encoded>



  



  &lt;div class=&#34;featured-image__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/robotics.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Featured Image&#34; class=&#34;featured-image&#34; style=&#34;width: ;height: ;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;robotics&#34;&gt;Robotics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robotics is the intersection of science, engineering and technology that produces machines, called robots, that substitute for (or replicate) human actions. As you have seen in the movie such as I robot, wall-e, Transformer etc. where robots are been there. As time passes technology also evolves not also that it gets smatter and smatter also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-a-robot&#34;&gt;What is a Robot?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/robotic-arm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Robotic Arm&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A robot is the product of the robotics field, where programmable machines are built that can assist humans or mimic human actions. Robots were originally built to handle monotonous tasks (like building cars on an assembly line), but have since expanded well beyond their initial uses to perform tasks like fighting fires, cleaning homes and assisting with incredibly intricate surgeries. Each robot has a differing level of autonomy, ranging from human-controlled bots that carry out tasks that a human has full control over to fully-autonomous bots that perform tasks without any external influences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;characteristics&#34;&gt;Characteristics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/robot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Robot Characteristics&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robots all consist of some sort of mechanical construction. The mechanical aspect of a robot helps it complete tasks in the environment for which it’s designed. For example, the Mars 2020 Rover’s wheels are individually motorized and made of titanium tubing that help it firmly grip the harsh terrain of the red planet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robots need electrical components that control and power the machinery. Essentially, an electric current (a battery, for example) is needed to power a large majority of robots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robots contain at least some level of computer programming. Without a set of code telling it what to do, a robot would just be another piece of simple machinery. Inserting a program into a robot gives it the ability to know when and how to carry out a task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots all consist of some sort of mechanical construction. The mechanical aspect of a robot helps it complete tasks in the environment for which it’s designed. For example, the Mars 2020 Rover’s wheels are individually motorized and made of titanium tubing that help it firmly grip the harsh terrain of the red planet.&lt;br /&gt;
Robots need electrical components that control and power the machinery. Essentially, an electric current (a battery, for example) is needed to power a large majority of robots.&lt;br /&gt;
Robots contain at least some level of computer programming. Without a set of code telling it what to do, a robot would just be another piece of simple machinery. Inserting a program into a robot gives it the ability to know when and how to carry out a task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;utilization-of-robotics&#34;&gt;Utilization of Robotics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the International Federation of Robotics, 1.3 million industrial robots will be in use by 2018. Robotics continues to emerge as a large and influential market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following five industries are utilizing this new technology to boost efficiency and convenience for both businesses and consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-health-care&#34;&gt;1. Health Care&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/surgical-robot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Surgical Robot&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Advances in robotics have the potential to change a wide variety of health care practices, such as surgery, rehabilitation, therapy, patient companionship, and everyday activities. Robotic instruments used in health care are not designed to take over the duties of health care professionals, but rather to make their work easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The da Vinci Surgical System, for example, utilizes the hand movements of the operating surgeon to control tiny, precise instruments inside the patient’s body. This allows for minimally invasive procedures in surgeries such as cardiac, colorectal, gynecologic, head and neck, thoracic, and urologic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For patients who have suffered strokes or spinal cord injuries, or who are paralyzed, robotic devices such as exoskeletons have the ability to assist and guide them during rehabilitation. In addition, robotic lifting machines can help nurses lift patients who are elderly or immobile. Companion and therapeutic robots such as Paro can also comfort patients with mental health issues with a system of sensors, microphones, and cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-agriculture&#34;&gt;2. Agriculture&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/farm-robots.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Farm Robots&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To help increase productivity while lowering overall costs, the agriculture industry has been actively working to adopt different forms of robotic technology. Farmers have already been using tractors and harvesters that are self-guided by GPS. Recently, there has been a rise in the experimental use of autonomous systems that automate operations like pruning, thinning, mowing, spraying, and weed removal. Sensor technology is also being utilized to manage pests and diseases that affect crops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-food-preparation&#34;&gt;3. Food Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/food-robots.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Food line robot&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One of the more extravagant advancements in robot technology will soon be available in the kitchen. Automated and intelligent robots — such as those invented by Moley Robotics — will be able to prepare and cook hundreds of meals in a home kitchen. This robotic chef will be controlled via a smartphone, and once the controller chooses a recipe and arranges pre-packaged containers of cut and prepared ingredients, the robot will be able to cook the predetermined meal quickly and efficiently. Moley Robotics is also developing a consumer-friendly version of a robot kitchen, which will include a built-in smart dishwasher and refrigerator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-manufacturing&#34;&gt;4. Manufacturing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/industrial-robot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Manufacturing&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Robotics are being used in many aspects of manufacturing to help increase productivity and efficiency while lowering production costs. Similar to the health care industry, many robots in manufacturing collaborate with workers to perform repetitive, monotonous, or intricate tasks under the worker’s guidance and control. With these machines, precision is valued more than speed, as is the ability to be reprogrammed for specific tasks of different sizes and complexities. Robotic manufacturing technology is also becoming safer to operate. Cameras, sensors, and automatic shut-off capabilities enable robots to sense and stay clear of humans in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-military&#34;&gt;5. Military&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/ArmyGroundRobot.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Army Ground Robot&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the military and public safety sectors, robotic technology is being applied in many areas. One highly visible area involves unmanned drones. These machines can be used for surveillance and support operations on the battlefield. Military drones flying over areas of war and conflict, in hostage situations, and for natural and manmade disasters are able to assess danger levels and provide soldiers and first responders with real-time information. Drones are revolutionizing disaster response since they can access hazardous areas with greater speed and precision without placing human responders in harm’s way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robotic devices are already establishing a wide presence in several commercial industries. As robotic technologies become more affordable, they will soon be available in various forms for consumers as well, with the ability to impact our lives in countless ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pros--cons&#34;&gt;Pros &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Cons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;pros&#34;&gt;Pros&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first and the foremost advantage of having robots in workplaces is their cost. Robots are much cheaper than humans and their cost is now decreasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a fact that we cannot compare human abilities with robots but robotic capabilities are now growing quickly. For example, if you run an essay writing service, you can use robots to perform every kind of research related to any subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because robots are more active and don’t get tired like humans, the collaboration between humans and robots is reducing absenteeism. The pace of human cannot increase hence robots are helping humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots are more precise than humans; they don’t tremble or shake as human hands. Robots have smaller and versatile moving parts which help them in performing tasks with more accuracy than humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that robots are significantly stronger and faster than humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots come in any shape and size, depending upon the need of the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots can work anywhere in any environmental condition whether it is space, underwater, in extreme heat or wind etc. Robots can be used everywhere where human safety is a huge concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots are programmed by a human; they cannot say no to anything and can be used for any dangerous and unwanted work where humans may deny to offer their services. For example, many robotic probes have been sent into space but have never returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots in warfare are saving more lives and have now proven to be very successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots are now being used in the chemical industry and can, for example deal with chemical spills in a nuclear plant, which would otherwise pose a major health concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing about robots is that they never get tired and can literally work on certain tasks 24 x 7. The human brain gets tired if it’s working continuously but robots never get tired of what they are programmed to do and they can work on certain tasks error free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cons&#34;&gt;Cons&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where robots are increasing the efficiency in many businesses, they are also increasing the unemployment rate. Because of robots, human labour is no longer required in many factories and manufacturing plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots can certainly handle their prescribed tasks, but they typically cannot handle unexpected situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ROI of your business may suffer if your operation relies on too many robots. They have higher expenses than humans, so at the end of the day you may not always achieve the desired ROI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots may have AI but they are certainly not as intelligent as humans. They can never improve their jobs outside the pre-defined programming because they simply cannot think for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots installed in workplaces still require manual labour attached to them. Training those employees on how to work with the robots definitely has a cost attached to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots have no sense of emotions or conscience. They lack empathy and this is one major disadvantage of having an emotionless workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robots operate on the basis of information fed to them through a chip. If one thing goes wrong the entire company bears the loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where a robot saves times, on the other hand it can also result in a lag. It is, after all, a machine so you cannot expect too much from them. If a robot malfunctions, you need extra time to fix it, which would require reprogramming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If ultimately robots would do all the work, and the humans will just sit and monitor them, health hazards will increase rapidly. Obesity will be on top of the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there are advantages, but there are disadvantages as well. It is the twenty first century and we cannot work without machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are still considered far more efficient than robots when it comes to decision making powers, handling difficult situations, brainstorming, and generally bringing a sense of emotion and empathy into a workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Technovision</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/robotics.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>robotics</category>
            
          
            
              <category>technology</category>
            
          
            
              <category>industrial automation</category>
            
          
            
              <category>factory automation</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>industrial automation</category>
            
          
            
              <category>robotics</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Industry 4.0</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      

    
  </channel>
</rss>