<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" 
  xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tiktok on Mistry Siddh - Get weakly news related to different kinds of news, tips, tricks, etc. If you have your own theory or story then comment down in the post.</title>
    <link>https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/tags/tiktok/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tiktok on Mistry Siddh - Get weakly news related to different kinds of news, tips, tricks, etc. If you have your own theory or story then comment down in the post.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><hosted>Netlify -- netlify.com</hosted>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 15:45:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/tags/tiktok/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    

      
      <item>
        <title>Facebook Rivals TikTok With Its Just Launched Collab Music App</title>
        <link>https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/facebook-rivals-tiktok-with-its-just-launched-collab-music-app/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 15:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 15:18:55 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/facebook-rivals-tiktok-with-its-just-launched-collab-music-app/</guid>
        <description>Facebook has officially announced its Collab app, which the social media platform previously launched as an experiment. To recall, Facebook started testing Collab, an invite-only beta, back in the month of May this year. TechCrunch was the first to report about the official launch of Collab.
It is said that with Collab, the social media giant wants to take on the likes of TikTok, one of the most popular short video apps available globally.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/collab.png&#34; alt=&#34;Collab&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook has officially announced its Collab app, which the social media platform previously launched as an experiment. To recall, Facebook started testing Collab, an invite-only beta, back in the month of May this year. TechCrunch was the first to report about the official launch of Collab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said that with Collab, the social media giant wants to take on the likes of TikTok, one of the most popular short video apps available globally. Just as TikTok, Collab allows users to create short music videos by combining up to three independent videos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the idea behind Collab is similar to TikTok, there are some differences as well. The app will allow users to club three different videos together and also let them post individual videos on the platform. These videos will be visible to a public &amp;ldquo;Collab&amp;rdquo; feed where users can view and play along with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to The Verge, the Collab app is available for free on the Apple App Store and can be downloaded. It should be up on the Google Play store as well. On that note, interested people must understand that the app is still not available in India, neither on the Apple App store or Google Play store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post the TikTok app ban in India, several made in India short video platforms have been developed. The TikTok app was banned in India earlier this year and it is still not available in the country. There were words to ban the app in the United States as well on account of security and privacy issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, we have seen Facebook launched Instagram Reels in India alongside a few other markets to take on the likes of TikTok. Reels has gained wide popularity in the country and partly been able to replace TikTok. Notably, Reels is a part of the main Instagram app and it isn&amp;rsquo;t a separate application.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/collab.png" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>Facebook</category>
            
          
            
              <category>Tiktok</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>social media</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
          
        
      </item>
      

    
  </channel>
</rss>