<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" 
  xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>welcome on Mistry Siddh - Get weakly news related to different kinds of news, tips, tricks, etc. If you have your own theory or story then comment down in the post.</title>
    <link>https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/categories/welcome/</link>
    <description>Recent content in welcome on Mistry Siddh - Get weakly news related to different kinds of news, tips, tricks, etc. If you have your own theory or story then comment down in the post.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><hosted>Netlify -- netlify.com</hosted>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 14:26:46 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/categories/welcome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    

      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome User</title>
        <link>https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/welcome_user/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 14:26:46 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 15:18:55 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/posts/welcome_user/</guid>
        <description>Hello Hello, hope you&amp;rsquo;re doing well in this coronavirus. let&amp;rsquo;s get started from introduction myself Mistry Siddh. Well I like to be lazy and don&amp;rsquo;t do any kind of work but I like to watch anime and have some snacks with also I love to read manga.
Many of you people may know what is manga and anime but for those who don&amp;rsquo;t know what is manga and anime I will explain you in simple way.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hello&#34;&gt;Hello&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, hope you&amp;rsquo;re doing well in this coronavirus. let&amp;rsquo;s get started from introduction myself Mistry Siddh. Well I like to be lazy and don&amp;rsquo;t do any kind of work but I like to watch anime and have some snacks with also I love to read manga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/Naruto.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Naruto&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of you people may know what is manga and anime but for those who don&amp;rsquo;t know what is manga and anime I will explain you in simple way. Manga is a comic book which you can buy it from store and read it some may have colored pages some may not have have color pages. &lt;del&gt;Manga is spoiler for anime watchers&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have never read the manga or seen anime then I whole heartily recommend you to start with Naruto any of the manga or anime. You will find tons of site for the manga and to watch. Naruto is a part of my life as if he is alive in myself, I started watching Naruto from 2012 and ended all chapters the manga&amp;rsquo;s and all the episodes of anime too. Naruto taught to me many things in my life when I was in the starting years of me college, when my college started I use to see many couples in canteen siting hand in hand. I was really jealous of them but anime taught that being jealous is a part of your life you have to experience everything emotion of your life if you have happiness in your life that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that you won&amp;rsquo;t have happiness. I whole heartily thank all the anime and manga character to give me a new life.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://www.mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/welcome.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>welcome</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>welcome</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
          
        
      </item>
      

    
  </channel>
</rss>