<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" 
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" 
  xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>vaccination on Mr. Blogger</title>
    <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/tags/vaccination/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vaccination on Mr. Blogger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><hosted>Netlify -- netlify.com</hosted>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 15:41:52 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    
        <atom:link href="https://mistrysiddh.tk/tags/vaccination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    

      
      <item>
        <title>Coronavirus News LIVE Updates: US Cases Top 25 Million</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/coronavirus-news-live-updates/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 15:41:52 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 13:31:58 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/coronavirus-news-live-updates/</guid>
        <description>Coronavirus News LIVE Updates: Tata in Talks to Launch Moderna Covid-19 Vaccine in India; US Cases Top 25 Million Coronavirus News LIVE Updates: Tata Medical &amp;amp; Diagnostics is said to have started initial discussions with Moderna Inc for a partnership to launch its COVID-19 vaccine in India, the Economic Times reported today. Tata could team up with the India&amp;rsquo;s Council of Scientific &amp;amp; Industrial Research (CSIR) to carry out clinical trials of Moderna&amp;rsquo;s vaccine candidate in India, the report added, citing officials familiar with the matter.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&#34;coronavirus-news-live-updates-tata-in-talks-to-launch-moderna-covid-19-vaccine-in-india-us-cases-top-25-million&#34;&gt;Coronavirus News LIVE Updates: Tata in Talks to Launch Moderna Covid-19 Vaccine in India; US Cases Top 25 Million&lt;/h2&gt;




  



  &lt;div class=&#34;featured-image__wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/biden-pres.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Featured Image&#34; class=&#34;featured-image&#34; style=&#34;width: ;height: ;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus News LIVE Updates: Tata Medical &amp;amp; Diagnostics is said to have started initial discussions with Moderna Inc for a partnership to launch its COVID-19 vaccine in India, the Economic Times reported today. Tata could team up with the India&amp;rsquo;s Council of Scientific &amp;amp; Industrial Research (CSIR) to carry out clinical trials of Moderna&amp;rsquo;s vaccine candidate in India, the report added, citing officials familiar with the matter. The Indian government this month gave emergency-use approval to a COVID-19 vaccine developed by Bharat Biotech International Ltd and state-run Indian Council of Medical Research, and another licensed from Oxford University and AstraZeneca PLC that is being manufactured by the Serum Institute of India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of coronavirus cases in the United States crossed 25 million on Sunday, a Reuters tally showed, as states accelerate their vaccine distribution and more infectious strains are found globally. States including North Dakota and West Virginia have injected more than 83% of their allocated doses into residents&amp;rsquo; arms, according to data from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention released on Sunday. Virginia administered the fewest doses, with 42% of the vaccines received. The United States has administered at least 21.8 million doses of COVID vaccines, to about 6% of its population. The two vaccines currently approved also require a second dose. Alaska leads the vaccine administration tally, with about 13% of its population vaccinated, followed by West Virginia, with 11%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Joe Biden will announce he is re-imposing a Covid-19 travel ban on most non-US citizens who have been in Britain, Brazil, Ireland and much of Europe, a White House official said Sunday, as the new administration ramps up its pandemic response. Biden will also extend the ban to travelers who have recently been to South Africa amid warnings that new, more transmissible coronavirus variants are already establishing themselves in the United States, the official said, confirming US media reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Israel on Sunday announced a week-long ban on most incoming and outgoing flights in a bid to slow the spread of new variants of the novel coronavirus. The measure will begin at midnight from Monday into Tuesday and remain in effect until Sunday, a statement from the prime minister&amp;rsquo;s office said. Exceptions will be made for cargo and firefighting flights, as well as trips for medical treatments, funerals and legal procedures. A panel of health and interior ministry officials will be able to issue exemptions on request &amp;ldquo;for humanitarian or personal needs&amp;rdquo;, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision came with the country in its third national coronavirus lockdown, initiated late December and extended on Tuesday until the end of the month due to a surge in Covid-19 deaths. Earlier Sunday, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu had announced his government&amp;rsquo;s intention to close the airport, as variants of the coronavirus have been detected in rising numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re closing the skies hermetically, except for rare exceptions, to prevent the entry of virus mutations, and to ensure that we make swift progress with our vaccination campaign,&amp;rdquo; he said ahead of a cabinet meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later Sunday, the health ministry announced it had identified cases of a coronavirus variant originating in Los Angeles. &amp;ldquo;In the health ministry&amp;rsquo;s central virus laboratory, a variant from Los Angeles has been located using a sequencing process,&amp;rdquo; the ministry said in a statement. &amp;ldquo;The person confirmed to have this variant has infected four other people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Variants from South Africa and Britain have also been found in Israel. Since the rollout of vaccinations last month, more than 2.5 million of Israel&amp;rsquo;s nine-million-strong population have been vaccinated, according to the health ministry. On Saturday, Israel began vaccinating teens aged 16-18, who need to sit final high school exams.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/biden-pres.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>corona</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>medical</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Facing new outbreaks, China places over 22 million on lockdown</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/china-places-on-lockdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 13:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 14:05:53 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/china-places-on-lockdown/</guid>
        <description>By Steven Lee Myers
When a handful of new coronavirus cases materialized this month in a province surrounding Beijing — apparently spread at a village wedding party — Chinese authorities bolted into action.
They locked down two cities with more than 17 million people, Shijiazhuang and Xingtai. They ordered a crash testing regime of nearly every resident there, which was completed in a matter of days.
 They shut down transportation and canceled weddings, funerals</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/lockdown.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;China&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By Steven Lee Myers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When a handful of new coronavirus cases materialized this month in a province surrounding &lt;code&gt;Beijing&lt;/code&gt; — apparently spread at a village wedding party — Chinese authorities bolted into action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They &lt;code&gt;locked down&lt;/code&gt; two cities with more than &lt;code&gt;17 million people&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Shijiazhuang and Xingtai&lt;/code&gt;. They ordered a crash testing regime of nearly every resident there, which was completed in a matter of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They shut down transportation and canceled weddings, funerals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and, most significantly, a provincial Communist Party conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this week the lockdowns expanded to include another city on the &lt;code&gt;edge of Beijing&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Langfang&lt;/code&gt;, as well as a county in &lt;code&gt;Heilongjiang&lt;/code&gt;, a northeastern province. Districts in Beijing itself, &lt;code&gt;the Chinese capital&lt;/code&gt;, also shut down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;More than 22 million people&lt;/code&gt; in all have been ordered to remain inside their homes — double the number affected in &lt;code&gt;January 2020&lt;/code&gt; when &lt;code&gt;China’s central government locked down Wuhan&lt;/code&gt;, the central city where the virus was first reported, in a move that was then seen as extraordinary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flare-ups remain small compared with the devastation facing other countries, but they threaten to undercut the success the country’s Communist Party has had in subduing the virus, allowing its economy to surge back after last year’s slump and its people to return to something close to normal lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The urgency of the government’s current response stands in contrast to that of officials in &lt;code&gt;Wuhan&lt;/code&gt; last year who feared a backlash if they disclosed the &lt;code&gt;mysterious new illnesses&lt;/code&gt; then emerging. Local officials there had gone ahead with a &lt;code&gt;Communist Party&lt;/code&gt; conference like the one now canceled in &lt;code&gt;Hebei&lt;/code&gt;, despite knowing the risk of the disease spreading among people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Wuhan, authorities have created a playbook that mobilizes party cadres to quickly respond to new outbreaks by sealing off neighborhoods, conducting widespread testing and quarantining large groups when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the process of infectious disease prevention and control, one of the key points is to seek truth from facts, to openly and transparently release epidemic information and never to allow covering up or underreporting,” the Chinese premier, Li Keqiang, said at a meeting Friday of the State Council, China’s Cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;China, a country of 1.4 billion people&lt;/code&gt;, has &lt;code&gt;reported&lt;/code&gt; an average of &lt;code&gt;109 new cases&lt;/code&gt; a day over the past week, according to a &lt;code&gt;New York Times database&lt;/code&gt;. Those would be welcome numbers in countries experiencing far worse — including the United States, which is averaging more than &lt;code&gt;250,000 new cases a day&lt;/code&gt; — but they are the worst in China since last summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;China’s National Health Commission&lt;/code&gt; has not reported any new deaths, but the &lt;code&gt;World Health Organization&lt;/code&gt;, which uses information from China, has &lt;code&gt;recorded 12 so far in 2021&lt;/code&gt;. The National Health Commission did not respond to requests to explain the discrepancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hebei, the province where the new outbreak has been concentrated, officials last week declared a “wartime state” that shows no sign of lifting soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the pandemic, officials have appeared especially worried about Beijing, home of the Communist Party’s central leadership. Last week, the &lt;code&gt;party secretary in Hebei, Wang Dongfeng,&lt;/code&gt; pledged to make sure the province was &lt;code&gt;“the moat to safeguard Beijing’s political security.”&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outbreaks, coming after so long with minimal cases, have increased anxiety across China, where residents in most places felt like the pandemic was a thing of the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;New cases&lt;/code&gt; have also been reported in the &lt;code&gt;northern province of Shanxi&lt;/code&gt; and the northeastern provinces of &lt;code&gt;Heilongjiang and Jilin&lt;/code&gt;. Shanghai on Wednesday urged residents not to leave the city and announced that people who had traveled to risky areas should quarantine themselves at home for two weeks and leave only after passing two tests, while those who had traveled to the &lt;code&gt;highest-risk areas&lt;/code&gt; faced quarantine in government facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Wuhan, &lt;code&gt;rumors swirled&lt;/code&gt; that the city could face a &lt;code&gt;new lockdown&lt;/code&gt;; while those appeared unfounded, officials noticeably stepped up temperature checks on some streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Shunyi, a district in Beijing’s northeast that includes Beijing Capital International Airport as well as rural villages, residents have been ordered to remain inside since a surge of cases just before the new year. At Beijing’s main railroad stations, workers sprayed down public spaces with disinfectant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a &lt;code&gt;taxi driver tested positive&lt;/code&gt; over the weekend in &lt;code&gt;Beijing&lt;/code&gt;, authorities tracked down &lt;code&gt;144 passengers&lt;/code&gt; for additional tests, according to The Global Times, a state tabloid. &lt;code&gt;Now anyone getting in a taxi or car service in Beijing has to scan a QR code from their phone, allowing the government to quickly trace them.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government has moved ahead on plans to &lt;code&gt;vaccinate 50 million people&lt;/code&gt; ahead of the &lt;code&gt;Lunar New Year next month&lt;/code&gt;, a holiday when hundreds of millions of people traditionally crisscross the country to visit their families. By Wednesday, more than &lt;code&gt;10 million doses had been distributed&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with the vaccinations, officials have already warned people not to travel ahead of the holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;“These measures, if well implemented, can ensure that no large-scale epidemic rebound occurs,”&lt;/code&gt; Feng Zijian, the deputy director of China’s Center for Disease Control, said at a briefing in Beijing on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the new restrictions have inconvenienced millions, there appears to be no significant public resistance to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;“As far as I am concerned, I think measures like a lockdown for the whole city are actually quite good,”&lt;/code&gt; said Zhao Zhengyu, a university student in Beijing who is now confined to her parents’ home in Shijiazhuang, where she was visiting during winter break when the outbreak there erupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many in the city feared a repeat of Wuhan’s lockdown, but she sounded unfazed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhao’s parents now work from home, picking up groceries only from a market in their residential compound. She lamented that she could not meet friends or study in the library but said learning online has become routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Perhaps we have gotten used to it,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response underscored how quickly the government mobilizes its resources to contain outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the lockdown was announced in Shijiazhuang on Jan. 6, authorities collected more than 10 million coronavirus test samples over the next three days — nearly one for every resident, officials said at a news conference in the city. Those tests turned up 354 positive results, although some of the cases were asymptomatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second round of mass nucleic acid testing began Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In effect, this is a kind of wartime system — using the means of wartime for social control in peacetime — and during a pandemic this wartime system works,” said Chen Min, a writer and former newspaper editor who goes by the pen name Xiao Shu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chen was in Wuhan last year when the city went into lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of the country’s governance gave it the tools to tackle the epidemic — even if some measures seemed over the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Chinese cities enforce a residential system — smaller ones have several hundred residents, big ones have tens of thousands — and by shutting the gates you can lock in tens of thousands of people,” Chen said in a telephone interview. “Now whenever they run into this kind of problem, they’re sure to apply this method. That would be impossible in Western countries.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/china-lockdown.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>corona</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>medical</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Bharat Biotech’s intranasal COVID-19 vaccine &#39;BBV154&#39;</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/bharat-biotechs-intranasal-covid-19-vaccine-bbv154/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 15:02:59 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 15:26:56 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/bharat-biotechs-intranasal-covid-19-vaccine-bbv154/</guid>
        <description>What you need to know about Bharat Biotech’s intranasal COVID-19 vaccine &amp;lsquo;BBV154&amp;rsquo;? Hyderabad: Bharat Biotech on Friday announced that it will begin the phase1 clinical trials of its new intranasal vaccine for the novel coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) in February-March this year. The development came days after the Hyderabad-based firm received the Drugs Controller General of India’s (DCGI) nod for its COVID-19 vaccine Covaxin. Covaxin, which is India’s first indigenously developed COVID-19 vaccine, has been given restricted (emergency use) approval for use along with Serum Institute’s Covishield developed by the Oxford University in collaboration with AstraZeneca.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-need-to-know-about-bharat-biotechs-intranasal-covid-19-vaccine-bbv154&#34;&gt;What you need to know about Bharat Biotech’s intranasal COVID-19 vaccine &amp;lsquo;BBV154&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/nasal-vaccine-against-covid-19.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Vaccination&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hyderabad&lt;/code&gt;: Bharat Biotech on Friday announced that it will begin the phase1 clinical trials of its new intranasal vaccine for the novel coronavirus (&lt;code&gt;SARS-CoV-2&lt;/code&gt;) in February-March this year. The development came days after the Hyderabad-based firm received the &lt;code&gt;Drugs Controller General of India’s (DCGI)&lt;/code&gt; nod for its COVID-19 vaccine &lt;code&gt;Covaxin&lt;/code&gt;. Covaxin, which is India’s first indigenously developed COVID-19 vaccine, has been given restricted (emergency use) approval for use along with &lt;code&gt;Serum Institute’s Covishield&lt;/code&gt; developed by the &lt;code&gt;Oxford University&lt;/code&gt; in collaboration with &lt;code&gt;AstraZeneca&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier in September, &lt;code&gt;Bharat Biotech&lt;/code&gt; announced that it has partnered with &lt;code&gt;Washington University School&lt;/code&gt; of Medicine in &lt;code&gt;St Louis&lt;/code&gt; for a novel &lt;code&gt;intranasal coronavirus vaccine (BBV154)&lt;/code&gt;. The phase 1 human clinical trials of the nasal COVID-19 vaccine will be &lt;code&gt;conducted in India&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Saint Louis University’s Vaccine&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Treatment Evaluation Unit&lt;/code&gt;. And here’s what we know so far about the company’s intranasal COVID-19 vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bbv154-to-be-a-single-dose-regimen&#34;&gt;BBV154 to be a single-dose regimen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bharat Biotech’s &lt;code&gt;BBV154&lt;/code&gt; (a novel adenovirus vectored, intranasal vaccine for COVID-19) will be a &lt;code&gt;single-dose regimen&lt;/code&gt;. According to the company, an intranasal vaccine stimulates broad immune responses at the site of infection (in the &lt;code&gt;nasal mucosa&lt;/code&gt;), which is essential for blocking both infection and transmission of the &lt;code&gt;SARS-CoV-2 virus&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;non-invasive-needle-free&#34;&gt;Non-invasive, needle-free&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of an intranasal vaccine is that it is simple to administer - the jab is administered to a person via the nose and does not require a needle or trained healthcare workers to give the vaccine. This also means eliminating needle-associated risks such as injuries and infections. The vaccine is also ideally suitable for children and adults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“An intranasal vaccine will not only be simple to administer but reduce the use of medical consumables such as needles, syringes, etc., significantly impacting the overall cost of a vaccination drive,” Dr Krishna Ella, Chairman and Managing Director of Bharat Biotech, had said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One drop of vaccine in each of the nostrils is sufficient,” he had said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;demonstrates-protective-efficacy&#34;&gt;Demonstrates protective efficacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company said its intranasal vaccine candidate has demonstrated unprecedented levels of protection in mice studies - with the technology and data having been published in the &lt;code&gt;prestigious scientific journal Cell&lt;/code&gt; and in an editorial in Nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mice and hamsters immunized with a single dose of &lt;code&gt;ChAd-SARS-CoV-2-S&lt;/code&gt; conferred superior protection against &lt;code&gt;SARS-CoV-2&lt;/code&gt; challenge, more so than one or two intramuscular immunizations of the same vaccine and dose. Post-challenge with SARS-CoV-2, viral clearance was observed in both lower and upper airways. Thus, intranasal immunization of ChAd-SARS-CoV-2-S can create an immune response in the nose, which is the point of entry for the virus - thereby protecting against disease, infection, and transmission,” the company said in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bharatbiotech.com/intranasal-vaccine.html&#34;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;code&gt;Bharat Biotech&lt;/code&gt; has successfully completed &lt;code&gt;enrollment of 25,800 volunteers&lt;/code&gt; for the crucial, phase 3 trials of Covaxin developed indigenously in partnership with the &lt;code&gt;Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR)&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;code&gt;National Institute of Virology (NIV)&lt;/code&gt;. The vaccine innovator said &lt;code&gt;Covaxin&lt;/code&gt; is a highly purified and &lt;code&gt;inactivated 2-dose&lt;/code&gt; COVID-19 vaccine, manufactured in a &lt;code&gt;Vero cell&lt;/code&gt; manufacturing platform with an excellent safety track record of more than &lt;code&gt;300 million doses&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/nasal-vaccine-against-covid-19.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>corona</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>medical</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>India Approves Two Vaccine Candidates but Let&#39;s Not Pretend Everything Is Okay</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/india-approves-two-vaccine-candidates-but-lets-not-pretend-everything-is-okay/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 14:22:07 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 15:26:56 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/india-approves-two-vaccine-candidates-but-lets-not-pretend-everything-is-okay/</guid>
        <description>Vaccination Approved In a short, eight-minute statement at 11 am on January 3, the Drug Controller General of India (DCGI) Dr V.G. Somani announced that his office had authorised two COVID-19 vaccine candidates for restricted use in the country. With the statement, India officially stood at the cusp of one of the world’s largest vaccination drives. But while the moment is suffused with hope, it will pay to remember at all times what exactly will happen from today: not a well-understood or well-planned event, and still hinged – for all the celebration of the science – on good luck.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vaccination-approved&#34;&gt;Vaccination Approved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a short, eight-minute statement at 11 am on January 3, the Drug Controller General of India (DCGI) Dr V.G. Somani announced that his office had authorised two COVID-19 vaccine candidates for restricted use in the country. With the statement, India officially stood at the cusp of one of the world’s largest vaccination drives. But while the moment is suffused with hope, it will pay to remember at all times what exactly will happen from today: not a well-understood or well-planned event, and still hinged – for all the celebration of the science – on good luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within hours of the UK approving AstraZeneca’s COVID-19 vaccine candidate, the company began rolling out thousands of doses for distribution among the country’s high-priority groups. This kind of speed would have been possible only if AstraZeneca had assumed the candidate would be approved and had amassed enough doses for distribution at the country’s doorstep. But while this attitude could seem presumptuous and off-putting at other times, it’s apparently necessary during an ongoing pandemic – especially with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/the-sciences/novel-coronavirus-d614g-mutation-rna-virus-replication-covid-19-pandemic/&#34;&gt;more contagious form&lt;/a&gt; of the virus showing up recently, and the AstraZeneca candidate being the cheaper option by far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least, this is the excuse many people, including some experts, are advancing for rushing various aspects of vaccine production and distribution as much as possible. This is unfortunate. The pandemic is only part of the reason, and perhaps even in the minority, among all reasons that AstraZeneca is accelerating its candidate’s availability. A major one is that the Pfizer/BioNTech collaboration has taken a big lead in the US and the UK with its high-efficacy mRNA vaccine candidate, with Moderna a close second in the US market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three candidates are two-shot vaccines, and the total population of the US and the UK is nearly 400 million. So given current manufacturing capacity, no single candidate will single-handedly be able to sate demands in both markets, especially since demand is also high. So all three candidates are certainly in contention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, these companies have all been making their moves with at least one eye planted on the stock-markets. Stories of Pfizer’s windfall and the profits for its CEO when its candidate was approved for emergency use in the US are already part of pandemic lore. According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/health/covid-19-vaccine-universally-available-big-pharma-monopolies/&#34;&gt;one estimate&lt;/a&gt;, the company is set to make $13 billion in profits in 2021 alone. So as such AstraZeneca is already late, and if it is to catch up, it must become available asap in the US and the UK, and try to press a first-mover advantage where it can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pressing-the-advantage&#34;&gt;Pressing the advantage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India is one such place. The Serum Institute of India has a deal with AstraZeneca to manufacture its candidate for sale in other markets, as well as to make and distribute doses for sale in India, under the name ‘Covishield’. On January 1, the subject expert committee of the Central Drugs Standard Control Organisation (CDSCO) recommended that the vaccine candidate be approved for restricted use. On January 3, DCGI Dr Somani approved the candidate, as well as Bharat Biotech’s counterpart, named Covaxin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speed is awe-inspiring – but in India, it may also be a quirk of doing business. As &lt;em&gt;The Wire&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://thewire.in/health/adar-poonawalla-serum-institute-covid-19-vaccine&#34;&gt;has reported&lt;/a&gt;, “American and European governments have promised vaccine-makers billions of dollars to offset potential losses” in exchange for the makers to start manufacturing even before candidates are approved. But at least as of August 2020, the Indian government hadn’t made any such promises, leaving only companies that could afford to write-off large losses with the ability to start manufacturing early. Serum Institute was one such company. Its CEO Adar Poonawalla &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/01/world/asia/coronavirus-vaccine-india.html&#34;&gt;told &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it wanted to get a head-start because it could afford to, after investing upwards of Rs 3,300 crore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Happy new year, everyone! All the risks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SerumInstIndia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@SerumInstIndia&lt;/a&gt; took with stockpiling the vaccine, have finally paid off. COVISHIELD, India&amp;#39;s first COVID-19 vaccine is approved, safe, effective and ready to roll-out in the coming weeks. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/TcKh4bZIKK&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/TcKh4bZIKK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Adar Poonawalla (@adarpoonawalla) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/adarpoonawalla/status/1345605880381784067?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, all of this is scant justification for how much we don’t know about Covishield, or about the other candidates for that matter – if only because we are at risk of fooling ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Covishield’s case at least, there is an unsettled dispute between one of its vaccine trial participants and Serum Institute. The former has sued the latter for Rs 5 crore, by way of compensation for a neurological side-effect that the participant has claimed arose as a result of being administered Covishield. Serum Institute subsequently threatened to counter-sue for Rs 100 crore, alleging defamation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Shreya Dasgupta &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/health/covid-19-serum-institute-clinical-trials-chennai-volunteer-communication-ethics-dcgi/&#34;&gt;reported for &lt;em&gt;The Wire Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Serum Institute’s response doesn’t inspire confidence in its version of events – more so since informed consent in the context of clinical trials is not as iron-clad an indemnification as some might think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AstraZeneca’s vaccine candidate is also knee-deep in trouble in the UK, where an advisory group to the government has expressed doubts about the company’s claim that the candidate could be more effective if the first of its two doses is halved in quantity. This claim arose from an accident during its phase 2 clinical trials, when a subgroup of participants received a full dose + half dose regimen by mistake, but which still reported 28 percentage points more efficacy. The company got in even more trouble after it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/the-astrazeneca-covid-vaccine-data-isnt-up-to-snuff/&#34;&gt;became known&lt;/a&gt; that it may have cherry-picked data from its trials to share with governments for approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serum Institute only appears to be following suit. The company is conducting bridging trials in India, which can help find if a vaccine candidate tested elsewhere will elicit an immune response in the Indian population as well. Out of a pool of 1,600 participants, Serum Institute submitted data pertaining to only 100 volunteers to the CDSCO’s subject expert committee, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/coronavirus-serum-institute-of-indias-covid-19-vaccine-covishield-likely-to-be-approved-for-emergency-use-in-india/article33472324.ece&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hindu&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. Bear in mind that this is a vaccine to be distributed to over a billion people in India alone, and the committee has recommended it based on data from only a hundred of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Bharat Biotech: the Covaxin vaccine candidate’s efficacy data isn’t in the public domain – nor are details from its phase 1 and 2 clinical trials and about how the company has estimated the figure &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/health/covid-19-bharat-biotechs-covaxin-expected-to-be-60-effective-company-says/&#34;&gt;to be around 60%&lt;/a&gt;. That the DCGI’s approval is &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/health/biocon-itolizumab-covid-national-task-force-19-dcgi-approval-phase-2-cdsco/&#34;&gt;entirely opaque&lt;/a&gt; only makes this more of a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sidestepping-criticism&#34;&gt;Sidestepping criticism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.thewire.in/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/03115608/Screenshot-2021-01-03-at-11.55.32-AM.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr V.G. Somani addressing the press on January 3, 2021. Source: PIB/YouTube&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not all. The head of the UK advisory group, Munir Pirmohamed, &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/health/still-in-the-weeds-uk-nod-for-astrazeneca-vaccine-raises-more-questions/&#34;&gt;recently said&lt;/a&gt; that when the group analysed the data AstraZeneca had submitted for its candidate’s approval, it found that the higher efficacy in the subgroup of participants that received the full-dose/half-dose regimen could in fact have been the result of a longer gap between the two doses, and not the altered dose volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thehindu.com/opinion/editorial/the-second-dose-the-hindu-editorial-on-covid-19-vaccine-clearance-in-india/article33475177.ece&#34;&gt;has since approved&lt;/a&gt; a strategy to distribute the first dose to recipients as quickly as possible, since there is enough data to believe it provokes an immune response. However, we don’t know how the strength and duration of the response will vary in time, and whether the candidate will be just as efficacious if the second dose is delayed by more than a certain period. And yet again there is a caveat: the strategy to increase the gap between the two doses may not just be because the efficacy may be higher, but also because AstraZeneca may be &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.box.com/s/uwwn2dv4o2d0ena726gf4403f3p2acnu&#34;&gt;having issues&lt;/a&gt; with supply!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn’t this a shoddy path to vaccine approval, full of serendipities and experimental manoeuvres? As drug-discovery chemist &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Dereklowe/status/1344644941339889669&#34;&gt;Derek Lowe said&lt;/a&gt;, the pandemic, and the virus’s new mutation that allows it to spread faster through populations, may still be able to make a good case to support this kind of breakneck speed – but neither the UK government nor anyone else actually knows what they are doing. It’s a dice-roll (with a somewhat loaded die, but still) to be performed with millions of people, in the hopes that a vaccine candidate will work as intended. And AstraZeneca is not alone here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Sandhya Srinivasan, consulting editor at the &lt;em&gt;Indian Journal of Medical Ethics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/health/covid-19-vaccines-immunisation-insufficient-tests-financial-stake-vaccine-related-injuries/&#34;&gt;wrote late last year&lt;/a&gt;, we don’t have vaccines – we have vaccine candidates. This is an important distinction because the candidates have been or are being tested in a way that doesn’t check if they’re good at preventing severe illness and if they are safe for the high-priority groups who will receive the first doses – especially the elderly. Both Srinivasan and S. Swaminathan, a retired scientist in New Delhi, have also &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/the-sciences/covid-19-vaccine-efficacy-clinical-trials-adverse-events-severe-disease-proven-technology/&#34;&gt;expressed concerns&lt;/a&gt; about clinical trials overestimating vaccine efficacy by relaxing the threshold of effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most pernicious defence of these practices has been to accuse anyone who asks uncomfortable questions of being “anti-vaxxers”. Anti-vaxx is short for ‘anti-vaccination’, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/health/mmr-vaccination-autism/&#34;&gt;movement opposed to using vaccines&lt;/a&gt; to eliminate diseases because its members believe vaccines &lt;em&gt;cause&lt;/em&gt; diseases instead. Anti-vaxxers are typically supporters of far-right ideologies, but those heaping the accusation on demands for accountability are assuming a similarly extreme, and unfeasible, position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In India at least, the drug approval process might as well not happen, considering the extent to which it is shrouded in secrecy, even as corporate leaders use high-handed tactics and even &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kiranshaw/status/1283371081089216512&#34;&gt;arguments of nationalism&lt;/a&gt; to shutdown complaints of malpractice and wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vaccine-apartheid&#34;&gt;Vaccine apartheid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piling on top of this is the newly emerging – but historically familiar – “vaccine apartheid”. As &lt;a href=&#34;https://theintercept.com/2020/12/31/covid-vaccine-countries-scarcity-access/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; on December 31, 2020, the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine candidate was tested in clinical trials with almost 44,000 participants across “Argentina, South Africa, Brazil, Germany, and Turkey as well as the US”. However,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argentina, South Africa, Brazil and Turkey will have to be satisfied with Pfizer’s gratitude, because … they won’t be receiving enough of the vaccine to inoculate their populations, at least not anytime soon. Meanwhile, the US and Germany — along with Canada and the rest of the EU — have contracted for enough doses of various COVID-19 vaccines to inoculate their populations several times over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar story of discrimination played out vis-à-vis severe adverse events during the trials of AstraZeneca’s candidate. When such an event &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.statnews.com/2020/09/08/astrazeneca-covid-19-vaccine-study-put-on-hold-due-to-suspected-adverse-reaction-in-participant-in-the-u-k/&#34;&gt;was reported&lt;/a&gt; in the UK trials, the company responded by temporarily halting the trials and launching an enquiry based on a set of predetermined, &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.thewire.in/the-sciences/covid-19-vaccine-clinical-trials-participant-illness-aefi-data-safety-what-next/&#34;&gt;well-understood guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. News of the event also hit the headlines worldwide within a day or two. Once the enquiry concluded, the trials resumed without any glitches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In India, however, Serum Institute claims it followed a similar process, as required under Indian law, but which culminated with the participant filing a case against the company. In addition, the event had occurred in early October but came to light only in late November. Other participants of the same trial also said they were contemplating legal action because they hadn’t been informed of the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the richer west, vaccine-makers’ attitude seems to be “what’s there to hide”. But in India, and other similar ‘developing countries’, it’s “what’s there to see”. This is why stakeholders – which is practically everyone – must ask more questions and seek more clarity about how vaccine candidates are being approved and sold in India. ‘Cancelling’ those who disagree would be tantamount to ‘cancelling’ ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/COVIshield.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>corona</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>medical</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mutant Coronavirus Stain</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/mutant-coronavirus-stain/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 17:14:35 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 15:18:55 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/mutant-coronavirus-stain/</guid>
        <description>New Coronavirus Strain As the world is set to welcome the New Year 2020, as the new corona virus strain which was been identified in United Kingdom (UK) which created a panic and worry all around the globe. Due to this all the researches had been scratching there head because there are nearly about 5 variant or types of corona virus where some of it only effect children&amp;rsquo;s and kill them in a week before the reports comes, and some type are effects human body parts and destroys it completely.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-coronavirus-strain&#34;&gt;New Coronavirus Strain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/vacine.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Vacine&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the world is set to welcome the New Year 2020, as the new corona virus strain which was been identified in &lt;code&gt;United Kingdom (UK)&lt;/code&gt; which created a panic and worry all around the globe. Due to this all the researches had been scratching there head because there are nearly about 5 variant or types of corona virus where some of it only effect children&amp;rsquo;s and kill them in a week before the reports comes, and some type are effects human body parts and destroys it completely. This mutant variant of the virus alarmed all the expert&amp;rsquo;s as well as Health and Safety departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-new-strain&#34;&gt;About new strain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/corona-testing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;corona testing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New COVID variant of the &lt;code&gt;SARS-COV-2&lt;/code&gt; virus has been termed as &lt;code&gt;VUI-202012/01&lt;/code&gt;, and its said to be &lt;code&gt;70% more contagious&lt;/code&gt; than the already existing one. In London and other part of the UK, this virus is evolving itself according to environment such as living plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/evolve-plants.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Evolving Plants&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This plants evolve according to the current situation of the growing world where we continually pollute environment in various way: air, water, trees land etc. even Mother Nature is finding it&amp;rsquo;s way to survive from the pollution created by the human being. We cut thousands of tree&amp;rsquo;s everyday, burn thousands of fuel and create global warming situation where ice of North Pole and South Pole are been melting also due to global warming ozone layer is been defeated due to that ultraviolet rays are entering into earth atmosphere, polluting oceans and rivers due to which many sea creatures has found dead on sea cost and beaches and not also that some fishes are forced to live in that polluted environment. We human being are the only one creatures who can talk and express it&amp;rsquo;s feeling to each others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-case&#34;&gt;Initial Case&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/london_england.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;London England&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around &lt;code&gt;Mid December&lt;/code&gt; this year in &lt;code&gt;UK&lt;/code&gt; there were new strain of CoronaVirus virus has been confirmed due to which the authorities announced that it was &lt;code&gt;OUT OF CONTROL&lt;/code&gt;, however  expect believed that the virus had been around from September itself but was not been spotted as &lt;code&gt;there were no large-scale infection&lt;/code&gt;, according to report &lt;code&gt;nearly about 60 percent&lt;/code&gt; people were been infected by the new strain of CoronaVirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reporting-country&#34;&gt;Reporting Country&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/world-map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;World Map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infections related to the new COVID-19 strain are, at present, heavily concentrated in the UK, resulting in several countries to temporarily suspend the arrival of citizens from the region. A number of cases have also been reported in South Africa, Denmark, Netherlands, Australia and Italy, while France recently suspected that the new variant might have entered the Western European country as well. &lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/coronavirus-mutations.jpg" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>corona</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>Covid19</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CoronaVirus Reaches End of Earth as Outbreak Hits Antartica</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/coronavirus-reaches-end-of-earth-as-outbreak-hits-antartica/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 14:16:47 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 15:26:56 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/coronavirus-reaches-end-of-earth-as-outbreak-hits-antartica/</guid>
        <description>Corona Reaches to Antarctica Finally Covid-19 has landed in Antarctica said by Chile&#39;s military this week, as health and army officials scrambled to clear out and quarantine staff from remote research station surrounded by ocean and icebergs.
Army force said at least 36 people has been infected at it&amp;rsquo;s Bernardo O&amp;rsquo;Higgins base, including 26 army personnel and 10 civilian contractors conducting maintenance at the base
The permanently staffed research station, operated by Chile&amp;rsquo;s army, lies near the tip of a Peninsula in Northernmost Antarctica, overlooking a bay often dotted with icebergs.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/antartica.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Antarctica&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;corona-reaches-to-antarctica&#34;&gt;Corona Reaches to Antarctica&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally Covid-19 has landed in &lt;code&gt;Antarctica&lt;/code&gt; said by &lt;code&gt;Chile&#39;s military&lt;/code&gt; this week, as health and army officials scrambled to clear out and quarantine staff from remote research station surrounded by ocean and icebergs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Army force said at least &lt;code&gt;36 people&lt;/code&gt; has been infected at it&amp;rsquo;s Bernardo O&amp;rsquo;Higgins base, including &lt;code&gt;26 army personnel&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;10 civilian&lt;/code&gt; contractors conducting maintenance at the base&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The permanently staffed research station, operated by Chile&amp;rsquo;s army, lies near the tip of a &lt;code&gt;Peninsula&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;Northernmost Antarctica&lt;/code&gt;, overlooking a bay often dotted with icebergs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Base personnel &lt;code&gt;are already properly isolated and constantly monitored&lt;/code&gt; by &lt;code&gt;health authorities&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;Magallanes&lt;/code&gt;, in Chilean Patagonia, the army said, adding there had so far been no complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research and military stations in Antarctica - among the most remote in the world - had gone to extraordinary lengths in recent months to keep the virus out, canceling tourism, scaling back activities and staff and locking down facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers with the British Antarctic Survey estimate about &lt;code&gt;1,000 people&lt;/code&gt; at &lt;code&gt;38 stations&lt;/code&gt; across the frozen continent had safely navigated the southern hemisphere winter without incident. But an uptick in travel to and from the region this spring and early summer have heightened infection risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/covid_19_100x100.png" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>corona</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>medical</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>COVID 19 Vaccination in US a &#39;Miracle&#39;: White House</title>
        <link>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/covid-19-vaccination-in-us-a-miracle-white-house/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 12:52:43 +0530</pubDate>
        <author>siddh.mistry396321@gmail.com (Mistry Siddh)</author>
        <atom:modified>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 15:18:55 +0530</atom:modified>
        <guid>https://mistrysiddh.tk/posts/covid-19-vaccination-in-us-a-miracle-white-house/</guid>
        <description>The development and distribution of COVID-19 vaccine in such a short span of time is a &amp;ldquo;miracle&amp;rdquo;, the White House has said, slamming a section of the US media for deriding President Donald Trump for promising Americans that the vaccine would be available by the end of this year.
US pharmaceutical giant Pfizer began shipping the first batches of its long-awaited and newly-authorised coronavirus vaccine out of a Michigan warehouse on Sunday, setting in motion the biggest vaccination drive in American history.</description>
        <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/white-house.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;white-house&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development and distribution of COVID-19 vaccine in such a short span of time is a &amp;ldquo;miracle&amp;rdquo;, the White House has said, slamming a section of the US media for deriding President Donald Trump for promising Americans that the vaccine would be available by the end of this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US pharmaceutical giant Pfizer began shipping the first batches of its long-awaited and newly-authorised coronavirus vaccine out of a Michigan warehouse on Sunday, setting in motion the biggest vaccination drive in American history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vaccine is offering hope in the fight against the COVID-19 pandemic that has killed over 300,000 Americans and infected 16 million people across the country. Johnnie Peoples, a 43-year-old survival flight nurse, became the first person to receive the vaccine at the University of Michigan Medical Center in Ann Arbor on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yesterday, the United States witnessed a medical miracle: The first doses of a COVID-19 vaccine were administered to frontline workers across the country. The President promised a safe and effective vaccine in record time, and President Trump delivered,&amp;rdquo; White House Press Secretary Kayleigh McEnany told reporters at a news conference on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are vaccines that he oversaw the development of, he has great confidence in, she said, adding that Trump wants to see all Americans get this vaccine, with the most vulnerable getting it first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;article, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were told, according to Healthline, quote, a vaccine will &amp;lsquo;still take more than a year to develop&amp;rsquo;. USA Today warned us that, quote, &amp;lsquo;despite medical researchers&amp;rsquo; progress&amp;rsquo;, a vaccine, quote, was &amp;lsquo;more than a year away&amp;rsquo;. And National Geographic even told us that achieving a vaccine within, quote, &amp;lsquo;a year to 18 months would be absolutely unprecedented&amp;rsquo;. These reports deserve their own fact check: false,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump has not only been an optimist to achieve a vaccine by the year&amp;rsquo;s end, but he has also been a leader, McEnany said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Through Operation Warp Speed, Trump, the businessman, and the President, as the innovator, has succeeded,&amp;rdquo; she asserted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump directed military logistics experts at the Department of Defense to partner with health experts at Health and Human Services to ensure prompt delivery of vaccines and equipment, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This includes the appointment of a four-star General, who oversees the global supply chain and readiness for the United States Army as Operation Warp Speed&amp;rsquo;s chief operating officer, she told reporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration, McEnany said, supported clinical trials by working to enrol participants through NIH-funded COVID-19 protection networks and provided funding and technical support through the National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Disease and Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump also directed industrial-scale manufacturing of vaccines to take place at its own risk before knowing whether these vaccines would be successful. It was a novel approach, indeed, to vaccine development, and led by Trump, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The results of these historic investments will benefit the American people and will mark the beginning of the end of the pandemic. As the first doses of the vaccine are delivered and administered, we urge all Americans to continue to wash your hands, socially distance, wear a mask when you are unable to do so,&amp;rdquo; McEnany said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We also encourage those at the state level to improve the early and aggressive use of monoclonal antibody treatments, especially among vulnerable Americans,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration led the way, approving monoclonal antibody treatments for outpatient use, issuing two emergency use authorisations in November. &amp;ldquo;Additionally, through HHS&amp;rsquo;s Office of the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, monoclonal antibody patient courses have been allocated to all 50 states. Together, these steps can play a significant role, changing the course of this virus. Thank you to President Trump,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
        <dc:creator>Siddh Mistry</dc:creator>
        <media:content url="https://mistrysiddh.tk/images/posts/vaccination.png" medium="image"><media:title type="html">featured image</media:title></media:content>
        
        
        
          
            
              <category>corona</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>medical</category>
            
          
            
              <category>vaccination</category>
            
          
        
        
          
            
              <category>World</category>
            
          
        
      </item>
      

    
  </channel>
</rss>